Good evening, everybody.
大家晚上好。
I'm Professor Russell Spriglia from the English Department.
我是英语系的罗素·斯普利亚教授。
And looking out into the audience, I see many who were in attendance last time.
从台下的观众中，我看到很多上次来过的面孔。
Tonight's distinguished speaker, Sloboj Žižek, visited us here at Seton Hall, which was just a little over four years ago now, back in October of 2018.
今晚的杰出演讲者，斯洛博热·齐泽克，上次访问我们席顿大学是四年多前的事了，那是在2018年10月。
So, because many of you are already familiar with him, rather than giving the typical academic introduction, you know, listing his many academic positions,
所以，因为你们许多人已经对他很熟悉了，我就不按典型的学术介绍方式，列举他的众多学术职位，
his most significant books, the, you know, the movies he's starred in, et cetera, et cetera.
他最重要的书籍，他主演的电影等等。
I'm just going to cut to the chase and simply say that Slavoj Zizek, who is visiting us all the way from Ljubljana, Slovenia tonight,
我只想直接说，今晚从斯洛文尼亚卢布尔雅那远道而来的斯拉沃热·齐泽克，
is not only among the most recognized and recognizable academics in the world today, but also among the most important and most indispensable.
不仅是当今世界上最受认可和最容易被认出的学者之一，而且也是最重要和最不可或缺的学者之一。
And so we're very fortunate to have him here with us again tonight, and I'd like to begin by thanking him, first of all, for coming back to see us at Seton Hall.
所以我们非常幸运今晚再次有他在这里，首先我想感谢他回到席顿大学来看我们。
This event is cosponsored by the Provost's Office, the Dean's Office of the College of Arts and Sciences, and the Department of English.
这个活动由教务长办公室、文理学院院长办公室和英语系共同赞助。
So I'd like to take this opportunity to also thank Provost Katya Passerini, Associate Provost and my colleague in English, Jonathan Farina,
因此，我也想借此机会感谢教务长卡特雅·帕塞里尼、副教务长兼我的英语系同事乔纳森·法里纳，
Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences, Jerita Frierson,
文理学院院长杰丽塔·弗莱尔森，
Assistant Dean of Finance and Administration, Sheila Riley,
财务与行政助理院长希拉·莱利，
and last but certainly not least, my department chair, Angela Wiesel.
以及最后但同样重要的，我的系主任安吉拉·韦塞尔。
All of these people were instrumental in helping to make sure that this event came through.
所有这些人都在确保这个活动顺利进行中发挥了重要作用。
I'd also like to thank Michael Riccardelli, Olivia Lason,
我还想感谢迈克尔·里卡德利、奥利维亚·拉森，
Eva Rose Menino, Michael Suppios, and Christopher Petruzzi,
伊娃·罗斯·梅尼诺、迈克尔·苏皮奥斯和克里斯托弗·佩特鲁齐，
all of whom helped either to promote this event or to make sure that we were able to properly livestream it and record it for those who are unable to be here with us in person tonight.
他们都在推广这个活动或确保我们能够适当地进行现场直播和录制，为那些今晚无法亲临现场的人提供服务。
So I'm not going to presume to anticipate Slavoj's answer to the question posed by the title of his talk,
所以我不打算试图预测斯拉沃热对他演讲标题提出的问题的回答，
why do we enjoy feeling ashamed, but what I would like to do before turning the microphone over to him is to very briefly provide a bit of framing or cognitive mapping For those who might be a little bit puzzled or perplexed by the title, why do we enjoy feeling ashamed?
《为什么我们享受感到羞愧的感觉》，但在把麦克风交给他之前，我想简要提供一些框架或认知图谱，以帮助那些可能对这个标题感到有点困惑或困惑的人。
And this, the idea for doing this came from as a direct result of my personal experience while promoting the event.
这个做法的想法直接源自我个人在推广活动时的经历。
While I was out and about putting up flyers for it across campus, around town,
我在校园里和镇上到处张贴宣传单，通过各种社交媒体网站和平台分享，
sharing it on various social media sites and platforms,
我得到的最常见反应，老实说，我会说大约七到八成的人，
the most common response I got, honestly, I would say like seven or eight out of 10 people,
当他们看到标题后立即回应，我不喜欢感到羞愧。
as they looked it over and saw the title, they immediately responded, I don't enjoy feeling ashamed.
现在，作为一个研究精神分析理论的人，这都是斯拉沃热的错，他直接影响了我，
Now, as someone who works in psychoanalytic theory, and this is all Slavoj's fault, he's a direct influence of Slavoj,
他是我的最伟大的老师，每当我得到这种回应（我不喜欢感到羞愧），我就忍不住想到弗洛伊德的一个著名轶事，这也是斯拉沃热喜欢讲的。
he's my greatest teacher, whenever I got this response, I couldn't help but think of one of Freud's famous anecdotes, and it's one Slavoj likes to tell.
你知道，弗洛伊德有一个病人，他问他，
You know, Freud has a patient, and he asks him,
作为对问题的回应，你知道，谁是，嗯，弗洛伊德问他，你梦中的那个女人是谁？
in response to the question, you know, who is, well, Freud asks him, who is that woman in your dream?
回答是，我不知道那个女人是谁，但我确定她不是我的母亲。
And the response is, I don't know who that woman was, but I'm sure it wasn't my mother.
对于弗洛伊德来说，这个回应，这就像是他所说的否定，或者德语中的“Verneinung”的一个典型例子。
And for Freud, this response, this is like a quintessential example of what he calls negation, or wennienung in German.
他继续说，你知道，这种回应，这样的回应，立刻就解决了问题，你知道，
And he goes on to say that, you know, this response, Such a response, it settles the matter, you know, immediately.
毫无疑问。
Beyond the shadow of a doubt.
我们可以绝对确定，这位病人梦中的女人是他的母亲，因为那个回应。
We can absolutely be sure that the woman in this patient's dream was his mother because of that response.
所以当大量的……大多数人对这个……当他们看到标题时的回应。
So when the vast amount of, you know, the majority of people responded to this, you know, while they're seeing the title.
我不喜欢感到羞愧。
You know, I don't enjoy feeling ashamed.
我很想做一个好的弗洛伊德学者并说，好吧，那么问题解决了。
I was so tempted to be a good Freudian and say, well, it's settled then.
你显然确实喜欢感到羞愧。
You clearly do enjoy feeling ashamed.
但实际上我没有这样做，顺便说一下。
But I didn't end up doing that actually for the record, so.
但我最终没有这么做。
Okay. Now, very briefly, I'm going to close this introduction shortly.
好的。现在，我很快就要结束这个介绍了。
But for those who responded in this way, you know, in the classic form of negation, the problem lies, of course, with the term enjoy, right?
但对于那些以这种方式回应的人，你知道，以典型的否定形式，问题当然出在“享受”这个词上，对吧？
With the suggestion that one could possibly enjoy feeling something as mortifying as shame.
暗示某人可能会享受感受像羞愧这样的羞辱感。
In much the same way, you know, Freud's patient preemptively
就像弗洛伊德的病人一样，他预先否定了梦中那个女人是他母亲的想法，因为这将表示某种被压抑的，你知道，俄狄浦斯欲望。
But what's absolutely crucial to stress here, and is there's a difference between enjoyment in the common everyday senses
但绝对关键的是要强调这里有一个区别，就是在日常常见意义上的享受
that we use the term like enjoying a nice cup of coffee in the morning or a sunset in the evening.
我们使用这个词的方式，比如早晨享用一杯美味的咖啡或者傍晚欣赏日落。
And enjoyment in the psychoanalytic sense,
与精神分析意义上的享受，这是弗洛伊德最伟大的传人，雅克·拉康，他用法语指定的术语，英语中没有好的等价词。
Enjoyment is close, but it's not quite good enough.
享受接近了，但还不够好。
The term jouissance, which is an enjoyment,
术语jouissance，这是一种享受，
as Freud would have put it, that is beyond the pleasure principle.
正如弗洛伊德所说，这是超越快感原则的。
It's an unconscious enjoyment in the repetition of something that, you know, undermines yourself, is not in your best interest.
这是一种在重复某事时的无意识享受，你知道，这种重复会损害自己，不符合自己的最佳利益。
So it's a pleasure in pain.
所以这是一种痛苦中的快乐。
It's not a, you know, a common sense of enjoyment.
这不是一种常识中的享受。
So I just want to conclude by stressing that out.
所以我只想通过强调这一点来结束我的话。
It's very important to keep in mind that fundamental distinction between the common everyday use of it
记住这个基本区别非常重要，
and this jouissance of excessive traumatic enjoyment that you don't really enjoy in the classic sense.
以及这种过度的、创伤性的享受的jouissance，你在经典意义上其实并不真正享受它。
So, okay, I've talked long enough.
好的，我已经说得够长了。
I've made you wait long enough.
我让你们等待得够久了。
So I'm just going to stop and ask you to please join me in welcoming back to Seton Hall my good friend, the one and only Slavoj Zizek.
所以我就不多说了，请大家和我一起欢迎我的好朋友，独一无二的斯拉沃热·齐泽克再次回到席顿大学。
I'm glad to be here again.
我很高兴再次来到这里。
I hope not the last time.
我希望这不是最后一次。
But let me first address a technical problem.
但让我首先解决一个技术问题。
Was it only my problem or your voice had a strange echo?
只有我一个人有这个问题还是你的声音有奇怪的回声？
It was a little bit difficult for me to follow it clearly.
我有点听不清。
Can you follow me clearly?
你能清楚地听到我吗？
It works.
可以。
Okay. Okay.
好的。好的。
It will be a relatively long talk with some video clips, so I hope not too boring.
这将是一次相对较长的演讲，并且会有一些视频片段，所以我希望不会太无聊。
Let me begin.
让我开始吧。
I want to begin with a well-known scene from Hitchcock's rather, Alfred Hitchcock's rather bad film Torn Curtain from 1966.
我想从希区柯克的一部相对较差的电影《撕裂的窗帘》（1966年）中的一个著名场景开始讲起。
The only outstanding scene in the film is that of the murder of Gromek,
电影中唯一出色的场景是格罗梅克的谋杀场景，
Stasi, Stadzicherkeit, his German secret police officer who suspects that Armstrong, played by Paul Newman, the movie's hero, did not sincerely defect to the East.
斯塔西，斯塔齐赫尔凯特，他是德国秘密警察官员，怀疑阿姆斯特朗（由保罗·纽曼饰演，电影的英雄）没有真心投诚到东方。
So Gromek follows Armstrong to a loan farm where Armstrong went to make preparations to return to the West.
所以格罗梅克跟踪阿姆斯特朗到一个偏僻的农场，阿姆斯特朗去那里是为了准备返回西方。
Gromek realizes that Armstrong is a double agent And as he is calling the police, a tortuous struggle begins that ends with Gromek being brutally slain by Armstrong.
格罗梅克意识到阿姆斯特朗是一个双重间谍。当他正在呼叫警察时，一场曲折的斗争开始了，最终以阿姆斯特朗残忍地杀害格罗梅克告终。
The by far best scene in the movie, which as Hitchcock put it, shows how difficult it is to kill a man.
迄今为止电影中最好的场景，正如希区柯克所说，展示了杀死一个人有多难。
Gromek's head is pushed into a gas oven where he slowly suffocates,
格罗梅克的头被推进煤气炉中，他慢慢窒息，
desperately waving his hands.
绝望地挥动着他的手。
Can we have the first?
我们可以放第一个吗？
It's four minutes long, but you will see what I will, that you draw from that scene.
它时长四分钟，但你们将会看到我从那个场景中提取出来的内容。
Why did I show you this clip?
为什么我要给你们看这个剪辑？
My point has nothing to do with the content, But I want to draw your attention to a shocking fact that I discovered only recently.
我的观点与内容无关，但我想吸引你们注意到一个令人震惊的事实，这是我最近才发现的。
Gromek, the bad guy, is played by Wolfgang Kieling,
格罗梅克，这个坏人，由沃尔夫冈·基林扮演，
who was at that time a well-known West German movie and TV star.
那时他是一个著名的西德电影和电视明星。
He acted also in some other Hollywood productions.
他还参演了一些其他好莱坞制作的电影。
And here comes the surprise.
这里有一个出人意料的地方。
During the post-production of this movie in Hollywood in August of 1965, the so-called Watts race riots took place, which were brutally suppressed by the police.
在1965年8月，这部电影在好莱坞后期制作期间，所谓的沃茨种族骚乱发生了，这场骚乱被警方残酷镇压。
There were around 50 people dead.
大约有50人死亡。
And you know what happened in real life?
你知道现实生活中发生了什么吗？
Killing the actor became disgusted with American society and as a result,
这场杀戮使这位演员对美国社会感到厌恶，结果，
after the film was released, he defected to East Germany in real life,
在电影上映后，他真的投奔了东德，
calling the United States, quote, the most dangerous enemy of humanity in the world today guilty of crimes against the blacks and the people of Vietnam," end of quote.
称美国是“当今世界上对人类最危险的敌人，对黑人和越南人民犯下了罪行”，引号结束。
The irony of his case is sublime, sorry, supreme.
他的案例的讽刺是崇高的，不，是至高的。
The production of a movie about a fake defection to the east to communist East Germany led to an actual defection to East Germany.
一部关于向东方、向communism东德假投诚的电影的制作，导致了一次真正的投奔东德。
A truly dialectical approach to the Cold War, I think, has to give space also to such peculiarities which disturb the simple opposition of democracy and totalitarianism.
我认为，对冷战的真正辩证法思考，也必须给予这样的特殊性以空间，这些特殊性扰乱了民主与极权主义简单对立的格局。
Today's killings, not to kill, but Wolfgang killings,
今天的“杀戮”，不是杀戮，而是沃尔夫冈·基林，
are precisely people like Assange or Snowden,
确切地说是像阿桑奇或斯诺登这样的人，
who although he didn't want to found years ago, you remember, the only safe place to stay in Russia.
虽然他多年前并不想这样，你还记得，唯一安全的地方是呆在Russia。
He is well aware that the reasons have nothing to do with Russia's love of freedom.
他非常清楚，这些原因与Russia对自由的热爱无关。
But these are paradoxes that we witness today.
但这些就是我们今天见证的悖论。
And such an approach is needed, again, especially today, when our disorientation is generalized.
再次，特别是在今天，当我们的迷失是普遍的时候，需要这样的方法。
Events we should be ashamed of occur everywhere.
我们应该感到羞耻的事件到处都有。
But should we be ashamed?
但我们应该感到羞耻吗？
How does shame function today?
羞耻今天如何发挥作用？
In his two revelations on shame,
在他关于羞耻的两个揭示中，
the Austrian philosopher Robert Faller convincingly refutes two common notions about shame, shame as opposed to guilt.
奥地利哲学家罗伯特·法勒有力地反驳了两个关于羞耻的常见观念，羞耻与内疚相对立。
The idea that shame comes from outside in contrast to guilt,
羞耻源于外界，与内疚形成对比，
which is your inner feeling and that shame comes from my failure,
内疚是你的内在感觉，而羞耻源于我的失败，
from being not good enough.
源于不够好。
Guilt comes in different grades.
内疚有不同的程度。
It involves rational argumentation, counter argumentation and the possibility of pardon.
它涉及理性论证、反论证以及赦免的可能性。
While shame overwhelms us all of a sudden, we just wish to disappear, no rational way out is offered to us.
而羞耻则突然压倒我们，我们只希望消失，我们找不到理性的出路。
Now, Fowler demonstrates how the role of shame changed in today's culture.
现在，法勒展示了羞耻在今天文化中的角色是如何变化的。
Shame is no longer the shame of failure or weakness, but the shame of an obscene too much, too muchness, which can be success itself.
羞耻不再是失败或软弱的羞耻，而是淫秽太多、太多的羞耻，而这也可以是成功本身。
I am not ashamed of my lack or insufficiency.
我不因为我的缺乏或不足感到羞耻。
I myself appear to myself as an obscene excess, an element out of place.
我自己在自己看来是一种淫秽的过度行为，一种不合时宜的元素。
I just want to disappear, sink into ground because I'm too fat,
我只是想消失，因为我太胖，
because I emit flatulence in public, whatever you want.
因为我在公共场合放屁，随便你怎么想。
So the subject perceives itself as an obscene excess, as an element that lacks its own place in the symbolic order, which defines the coordinates of our reality.
因此，主体将自己视为一种淫秽的过度，作为一个在象征秩序中缺乏自己位置的元素，而象征秩序定义了我们现实的坐标。
Shame is not triggered by not enough, but by too much.
羞耻不是由不够引发的，而是由太多引发的。
It comes from below, not from above.
它来自下方，而不是上方。
This is also why the weird agency of what Fowler called innocent observer is an agent of pure appearance
这也是为什么法勒称之为无辜观察者的奇怪代理是一种纯粹表面现象的代理
and the duty of our ego is to maintain the appearances to prevent that the innocent observer will notice them.
而我们的自我责任是维持表面现象，以防无辜观察者会注意到它们。
What do I mean by this?
我这是什么意思？
Fowler deploys the functioning of this innocent observer perfectly.
法勒完美地展示了这种无辜观察者的功能。
Shame doesn't arise when all know about the painful matter.
当所有人都知道那件痛苦的事时，羞耻并不会出现。
Shame bursts out only when an as-is, as if we don't know, breaks down.
只有当一种似乎我们不知道的状态崩溃时，羞耻才会爆发出来。
When the attempt to maintain a public secret fails, shame arises in everybody who is present."
当试图维持一个公共秘密失败时，羞耻会在所有在场的人中产生。
This means that shame is not simply external.
这意味着羞耻不仅仅是外在的。
I can feel ashamed also when I am alone.
即使我一个人时，我也能感到羞耻。
What we call manners or tact means that we learn to pretend that the big other didn't notice the disturbing element.
我们所说的礼貌或得体意味着我们学会假装大他者没有注意到那个扰乱的元素。
This role of the innocent observer, the guardian of appearances, also accounts for the strange fact that I can feel shame for others who should be ashamed of themselves.
无辜观察者的角色，表面现象的守护者，也解释了一个奇怪的事实：我可以为那些应该为自己感到羞耻的人感到羞耻。
When the innocent observer registers the excess, we all feel equally ashamed since it became obvious that we all knew the reality and just discreetly ignored it.
当无辜的观察者注意到这种过度行为时，我们都感到同样的羞愧，因为很明显我们都知道现实，只是小心翼翼地忽略了它。
Again, let me further clarify this.
再次，让我进一步阐明这一点。
Let's say that somebody in a closed social circle, like behind a large table, does something socially inappropriate, like emit a loud flatulence.
比方说，在一个封闭的社交圈子里，像是围着一张大桌子，有人做了一些社交上不适当的事，比如大声放屁。
The proper thing to do is not to smile at him kindly with the message, okay, you did it, no problem.
正确的做法不是友好地对他微笑，传达信息，好吧，你做了，没问题。
The proper thing is to ignore it totally, to go on as if nothing happened.
正确的做法是完全忽视它，继续前进，就好像什么都没发生。
Now what do I mean by this agency of pure appearance?
现在我所说的纯粹表面现象的代理是什么意思？
You were, I was often in a situation, let's say again there are four or five people and you know something dirty, dramatic about one of the persons there.
你我经常处于这样的情况，比如说再次有四五个人，你知道其中一个人有些不堪的、戏剧性的事情。
You know and you know that everybody else knows and they all know that everybody knows.
你知道，你知道其他所有人也知道，他们都知道每个人都知道。
But, nonetheless, the moment you mention publicly this fact, everybody is ashamed.
但是，尽管如此，一旦你公开提及这个事实，每个人都会感到羞耻。
This is the best case, I think, or example of what Lacan means by the big other, the agent of appearances.
我认为，这是拉康所说的大他者、表面现象的代理的最佳案例或例子。
Now let's go to politics.
现在让我们谈谈政治。
Stalinism is perhaps the clearest political case of such an innocent observer.
Stalinism或许是这种无辜观察者的最清晰的政治案例。
However, we all know how absolutely crucial appearances were in Stalinism.
然而，我们都知道在Stalinism中表面现象是绝对重要的。
The Stalinist regime reacted with total panic whenever there was a threat that appearances will be disturbed.
Stalinism政权对任何可能扰乱表面现象的威胁都作出了全面的恐慌反应。
Let me just recall why, I wonder if you knew this, why it never reigned during the first of May parade in Moscow in Stalinist times.
让我回忆一下，我想知道你是否知道这个，为什么在Stalinist时代的莫斯科五一游行期间从不下雨。
The authorities feared that the rain disturbing the parade would be perceived as an indication that the Communist Party is not all-powerful.
当局担心雨水干扰游行会被视为Communist Party不是全能的迹象。
So they sprayed the sky above Moscow with gases which prevent the formation of clouds.
所以他们在莫斯科上空喷洒化学气体以防止云层形成。
What characterizes Stalinism is precisely this conjunction of raw, brutal terror and the need to protect appearances.
Stalinism的特点正是这种原始、残酷的恐怖与保护表面现象的需要并存。
Even if we all know something is not true,
即使我们都知道某些事情不是真的，
the big other of appearances should not notice it.
表面现象的大他者不应该注意到它。
That's why from 1956, the 20th Congress of Communist Party when Khrushchev rendered publicly some of the Stalinist crimes was such a trauma.
这就是为什么从1956年，Communist Party第20次代表大会上，赫鲁晓夫公开了一些Stalinism的罪行，成为了一个如此巨大的创伤。
You know that there were doctors in the background and carefully controlling it.
你知道，当时有医生在场后方，小心地控制着情况。
There were six to seven direct heart attacks, but why?
有六到七人直接心脏病发作，但为什么？
Nobody learned anything new.
没有人了解到任何新东西。
The shock was that this was rendered public.
震惊的是这些被公开了。
So where are we with this today?
那么，今天我们处于什么情况？
Let me take a recent example, maybe you know this clip from China.
让我举一个最近的例子，也许你们知道这个来自中国的片段。
The process of choosing seven members of the standing committee of the Politburo, the real seat of power in today's China, is totally obscure.
选择政治局常委会的七名成员的过程，今天中国真正的权力中心，是完全不透明的。
It happens behind closed doors.
这一切运行在被关闭的大门之后。
But at the last Congress, now a couple of weeks ago, an unexpected crack appeared in this monolithic edifice.
但在上一次大会上，现在几周前，这个单一的体制中出现了一个意料之外的裂缝。
The former, before Xi, Chinese President Hu, Xi's predecessor as the party leader was unceremoniously dragged off stage shortly after foreign media came in.
前中国国家主席胡锦涛，在外国媒体进入后不久，就被无礼地从舞台上拖走，他是习近平的前任党领导人。
He looks disoriented and as two assistants help him stand, he speaks briefly with Xi'
他看起来迷茫，当两名助手帮助他站立时，他与习近平简短交谈，
whom he had been sitting next to in the front row.
他之前一直坐在前排与习近平相邻。
Don't be afraid, this is one minute even less.
别害怕，这只有一分钟甚至更少。
Why I found this almost a historical event?
为什么我认为这几乎是一个历史性的事件？
Although the official comment just mentioned afterwards the bad health and momentary weakness of Hu, Hu is dragged out, whose resistance and defiance were clearly visible.
尽管官方评论事后只是提到了胡锦涛的健康不佳和短暂的虚弱，但他被拖出去时的抵抗和挑衅是显而易见的。
For a moment, the smooth appearance was disturbed.
片刻之间，平滑的表面现象被打扰了。
Why did this happen?
为什么会发生这种情况？
There is, and discreetly friends from China told me this,
有，来自中国的朋友悄悄告诉我，
it wasn't that who was resisted,
不是胡锦涛在抵抗，
she's total power and wanted to protest.
也不是他完全反对权力并想要抗议。
No, it was all staged.
不，这一切都是有预谋的。
So, I like this point that the very disturbance of perfect appearance was staged.
所以，我喜欢这一点，即完美表面现象的扰乱本身就是有预谋的。
The first indication is that this incident occurred one minute after cameras from international TV were turned on, so that the whole world saw it.
第一个迹象是，这一事件发生在国际电视台的摄像机开启后一分钟，因此全世界都看到了它。
So the mask of appearance did not fall down.
所以表面现象的面具没有掉落。
It was intentionally taken down.
它是有意被摘下的。
He himself staged this incident to render visible his brutal power.
他自己策划了这一事件，以展示他的残酷权力。
However this reading indicates that the new Chinese leadership can no longer cling to
然而，这种解读表明，新的中国领导层已经不能再依赖于不受干扰的表面现象，它必须扰乱这些表面现象以确立其全面的权威。
Again, I think this is a very pessimist sign because you know Chinese were really obsessed by undisturbed appearance.
再次，我认为这是一个非常悲观的信号，因为你知道，中国人真的很着迷于不受干扰的表面现象。
To give you another example, you know the big introductory at the beginning parade which took place a couple of years ago, six, seven, when there were the Summer Olympics in Beijing.
给你举另一个例子，你知道几年前，六、七年前，在北京举行的夏季奥运会开幕式，
They were staged by Zhang Ki-mo, maybe you know him, the popular Chinese movie director who did Hero and other movies.
它们是由张艺谋策划的，也许你知道他，这位中国著名电影导演，拍摄了《英雄》等电影。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
The shock.
令人震惊的是。
The Chinese were the party.
中国Communist Party非常害怕出错
They were so afraid that something will go wrong
并扰乱表面现象，以至于当真正的游行进行时，
and disturb the appearance that while the real parade went on what the world saw on TV was a pre-recording of earlier staging of the same parade.
世界在电视上看到的是之前预录的同一游行的演练。
so that they could be absolutely sure that nothing will go wrong.
这样他们可以绝对确信没有任何问题。
So let me go on.
让我继续。
So they wanted to, they experienced if the perfect appearance is disturbed, it's shame.
所以他们想要，他们经历了如果完美的表面现象被扰乱，那就是羞耻。
It's total shame.
这是彻底的羞耻。
It shouldn't happen.
这不应该发生。
And again, as I already said,
再次，正如我已经说过的，
this is what I found nonetheless fascinating, especially with regard to what goes on today in classical communism.
尽管如此，我发现这非常迷人，特别是关于今天在传统communism中发生的事情。
Again, as I already said, it's extremely brutal,
再次，正如我已经说过的，它极其残酷，
but at the same time it's incredibly afraid of the slightest disturbance.
但同时它对最轻微的扰乱感到极度恐惧。
And I had, when I was much younger, in late 70s, I was the editor, one of the co-editors of a journal and we published some poem.
当我还很年轻的时候，在70年代末，我是一个期刊的编辑之一，我们发表了一些诗歌。
We thought nothing special, but then some lines it was possible to read them as a veiled critique of the communist party.
我们认为没什么特别的，但是其中一些行可以被解读为对Communist Party的隐晦批评。
And there was a special meeting of the central committee.
中央委员会召开了一个特别会议。
There was a panic in the party.
党内出现了恐慌。
No wonder.
难怪。
I think it was Brodsky, the Russian immigrant poet, who said,
我认为是布罗茨基，那位Russia移民诗人，曾说过，
and in some sense, it's not just a cynical joke.
在某种意义上，这不仅仅是一个玩世不恭的笑话。
It's true that at no time in human history, poetry was held at such high place than in Stalinism.
在人类历史上的任何时期，诗歌都未曾像在Stalinism时期那样被高度重视。
People got shot for a wrong line in a poem and so on.
人们因为诗中的一行错误而被枪决等等。
The irony of my case was that if there were to be no panic from the party, nothing would have happened, nobody would have noted that stupid poem.
我的案例的讽刺在于，如果Party没有产生恐慌，什么都不会发生，没有人会注意到那首愚蠢的诗。
So now I come to the point that you mentioned.
所以现在我来到你提到的那个观点。
The excess which causes shame is profoundly linked to some kind of surplus enjoyment.
导致羞耻的过度行为与某种过度的享受有着深刻的联系。
I feel shame when doing something that I secretly enjoy, like the same tasteless example emitting flatulence.
当我做一些我秘密享受的事情时，我会感到羞耻，比如同样低俗的例子，放屁。
Plus, and this reflexive term is crucial,
此外，这个反思性术语是关键，
I enjoy this shame itself.
我享受这种羞耻本身。
In some of his acts, but not all of them, Trump,
在他的一些行为中，但不是全部，特朗普，
Donald Trump, acts without shame.
唐纳德·特朗普，表现得毫无羞耻感。
The liberal leftists feel shame for him.
自由派左翼为他感到羞耻。
And this shame attributed to others is It is, in itself, a source of pleasure.
这种归咎于他人的羞耻，本身就是快乐的来源。
I enjoy others feeling shame for what I am doing.
我享受别人为我所做的事情感到羞耻。
However, Trump's shamelessness is not unlimited.
然而，特朗普的无耻并非无限。
Say, he would never shamelessly claim he is bisexual or gay.
比如，他永远不会无耻地声称自己是双性恋或同性恋。
In his eyes, those whom he dismisses as non-patriotic should be ashamed of themselves.
在他眼中，那些他认为不爱国的人应该为自己感到羞耻。
But in contrast to the liberal left, Trump would not feel himself ashamed on behalf of what the left is doing.
但与自由派左翼相反，特朗普不会因为左翼所做的事情而感到羞耻。
And what about today's woke left?
那今天的觉醒左翼呢？
I think Fowler is right to point out that we often have shame instead of argumentation.
我认为法勒正确地指出，我们经常有羞耻感而不是辩论。
Instead of a rebellious, enlightening left, ready to debate every question with its enemy since it feels assured about its better arguments,
而不是一个准备与敌人就每个问题进行辩论的叛逆、启蒙左翼，因为它确信自己有更好的论点，
now a fussing pseudo-left appears which fears argumentative confrontation and wants to close the mouth, especially to its own people.
现在出现了一个害怕论证对抗并希望封住嘴巴的伪左翼，特别是对其自己的人。
End of quote.
引号结束。
So I think the lesson of this is that shame is simply not reliable.
所以我认为这的教训是羞耻感根本不可靠。
You mentioned to me this afternoon in Mark Twain's Tom Sawyer.
你今天下午提到了马克·吐温的《汤姆·索亚历险记》。
You remember that wonderful moment when Tom does a good thing.
你记得那个美妙的时刻，汤姆做了一件好事。
He helps, I think, the black.
他帮助了，我想是黑人。
Sorry?
对不起？
A Huck Finn does this, yeah.
是哈克·费恩做的，是的。
I was always on Huck Finn's side, his bed, yeah.
我一直站在哈克·费恩这边，他的床，是的。
He helps the black Jim, the slave, escape, but he feels ashamed of it.
他帮助黑人吉姆，这个奴隶逃跑，但他对此感到羞耻。
It's an obvious case of how the truth is here on the side of his act, not his inner feeling.
这是一个明显的例子，说明事实是站在他的行为一边，而不是他的内心感受。
So we should move from shame to critical examination of the entire situation including shame itself.
因此，我们应该从羞耻转向批判性地审视整个情况，包括羞耻本身。
Yes, the first step should be it's horrible when you see no shame when something shameless is happening.
是的，第一步应该是，当发生无耻的事情而看不到羞耻感时，这是可怕的。
But then we should go on.
但然后我们应该继续。
So, let me give you an example of this, which again, there is nothing obscene, violent,
所以，让我给你举一个这方面的例子，再次，这里没有什么淫秽、暴力，
but it shocked me.
但它令我感到震惊。
Now, a week ago, on October 23rd, a video clip was released which reportedly shows
现在，一周前，10月23日，一个视频片段被发布，据报道显示
the Russia's Chechen Republic leader, Ramzan Kadyrov, being given three Ukrainian prisoners of war by his teenage son.
Russia车臣共和国领导人拉姆赞·卡德罗夫，由他的小儿子们送给他三名Ukraine战俘。
His teenage son, his three sons, 16, 14 years old, went,
他的小儿子们，他的三个儿子，16岁，14岁，
that's the official myth, as volunteers to Ukraine.
那是官方的神话，作为志愿者去了Ukraine。
And they got, came back with three prisoners and they give them as a present to his father.
并且他们带回了三名俘虏，作为礼物送给他的父亲。
Short clip, very short clip.
非常短的剪辑。
16 years old kid gives his father three prisoners as a gift,
16岁的孩子把三名俘虏作为礼物送给他的父亲，
as if prisoners of war are private property and even miners can own them.
好像战俘是私人财产，甚至未成年人也可以拥有他们。
Plus, what I found most shocking is the fact that this is publicly,
另外，我觉得最震惊的是这件事公开地，
that this is recorded and publicly displayed.
这被记录下来并公开展示的事实。
I mean, the question is how can something like this happen?
我的意思是，怎么会发生这样的事情？
This utter obscenity.
这种彻底的淫秽。
But what about the Western folk left?
但西方的觉醒左翼呢？
Now comes trigger warning.
现在来一个触发警告。
You will probably not agree with what I will say.
你可能不会同意我接下来要说的内容。
Towards the end of October of this year, Gonville and Caius College in Cambridge.
今年10月末，剑桥的冈维尔与凯斯学院
Cambridge, not here, Massachusetts, England, was hosting a talk by Helen Joyce, known for her view that men and women are being redefined by trans activists, with laws and policies
剑桥，而不是英国马萨诸塞州，正在主持海伦·乔伊斯（Helen Joyce）的一场演讲，她因认为跨性别活动人士正在重新定义男性和女性的观点而闻名，
reshaped to privilege self-identified gender identity over biological sex.
法律和政策也被重新调整，使自我认同的性别认同优先于生物性别。
Joyce unambiguously supports trans rights.
乔伊斯明确支持跨性别者的权利。
What she rejects is gender identity ideology, the idea that people should count as men or women according to how they feel and what they declare instead of their biology.
她反对的是性别认同意识形态，即人们应根据他们的感受和他们宣称的内容而非他们的生物性别来被视为男性或女性的观点。
Now, students at this college have launched protests with the college's LGBT plus representatives
现在，该学院的学生已向该学院的 LGBT+ 代表发起抗议，要求取消乔伊斯的出席，因为他们一致对此类观点的平台化感到厌恶。
Shooters were even opening a safe space, welfare, tearoom for students during the talk, blaming understandable hurt and anger for many students, staff and fellows caused by this invitation.
反对者甚至在演讲期间为学生开放了一个安全空间、福利、茶室，并指责这次邀请给许多学生、教职员工和同事造成了可以理解的伤害和愤怒。
The college's master joined them saying that while freedom of speech is a fundamental principle People on some issues which affect our community, we cannot stay neutral.
学院的院长加入他们，表示虽然言论自由是一个基本原则，但在影响我们社区的某些问题上，我们不能保持中立。
Now first my theoretical position here.
现在首先是我的理论立场。
I disagree with both polls in this conflict because I think the opposition between biology and what I feel and declaring what I feel is not exhaustive.
我不同意这场冲突中的双方，因为我认为生物学与自己的感受之间的对立以及对自己的感受的宣告并不详尽。
Where, and here is my criticism of some of this free choice of gender ideology, where is Freud here?
这里是我对这种自由选择性别意识形态的一些批评，弗洛伊德在哪里？
Where is the Freudian subject of the unconscious, which is neither biological nor a matter of feeling?
弗洛伊德的无意识主体在哪里，它既不是生物的也不是感觉的问题？
We become sexual subjects when our biological features get mediated by complex symbolic structures.
当我们的生物特征受到复杂的符号结构的调节时，我们就成为性主体。
Structures which work at a different level than our feelings.
结构的运作水平与我们的感受不同。
No matter how sincere, feelings may deceive.
无论感受多么真诚，它们都可能欺骗我们。
But nonetheless, I think that debating the role of biology or social symbolic structures in the formation of our sexuality is a legitimate topic.
但尽管如此，我认为争论生物学或社会象征结构在我们性行为形成中的作用是一个合理的话题。
How fragile the opponents of Joyce's appearance must be if they experience such a debate as something so threatening that they even need a safe space to protect them?
如果乔伊斯的反对者因为这样的辩论感到如此威胁，以至于他们甚至需要一个安全空间来保护自己，他们的立场有多脆弱？
Is it not that their refusal of debate betrays a fear that such a debate may render palpable the weakness of their position?
他们拒绝辩论是否暴露了一种恐惧，即这样的辩论可能会使他们立场的弱点变得明显？
Plus, are they aware that the logic of my identity is what I feel, if I feel a man, a woman, a trans, and I declare what I feel, can also be used in a directly racist and sexist way.
另外，他们是否意识到我的身份逻辑就是我的感受，如果我感觉一个男人、一个女人、一个跨性别者，并且我声明我的感受，也可以直接以种族主义和性别歧视的方式使用。
A full-blooded heterosexist would also need a safe space to avoid LGBT plus persons by whom he is anonymously disgusted.
一个纯正的异性恋主义者还需要一个安全的空间来避开 LGBT 以及他匿名厌恶的人。
I'm not agreeing with him.
我不同意他的观点。
I just claim again that this idea of my identity is what I feel, immediately experience and declare.
我再次声称，这种我的身份是我所感受、直接体验并宣称的想法。
It proceeds as if there was no Freud, no divided subject,
就好像没有弗洛伊德、没有分裂的主体、没有精神分析等等。
Duane Roussel, my Canadian friend, characterizes woke as racism in the time of the many without the one.
我的加拿大朋友杜安·鲁塞尔将觉醒描述为"众多中没有一"的时代的种族主义。
This may appear problematic, but I think it hits the mark in an almost exact opposite
这可能看起来有问题，但我认为它与传统的种族主义几乎完全相反，
to the traditional racism which fights against a foreign intruder posing a threat to the of the one, say immigrants and Jews to our nation,
传统的种族主义反对对我们国家构成威胁的外国入侵者，例如移民和犹太人对我们国家的威胁，
Vogue reacts to those who are suspected not to truly abandon all forms of the one, patriots, proponents of patriarchal values, and so on.
《Vogue》（译注：知名的时尚与生活方式杂志）对那些被怀疑没有真正放弃一切形式的人、爱国者、父权价值观的支持者等做出反应。
With all its declared opposition to the new forms of barbarism, the Vogue left fully participates in it, promoting and practicing a flat discourse without irony.
尽管《Vogue》左派公开反对新形式的野蛮行径，但它也充分参与其中，提倡和实践一种没有讽刺意味的平淡话语。
Although it advocates pluralism and promotes difference,
尽管它提倡多元化并推广差异，
its subjective position of annunciation,
但其宣告的主观位置，它所代表的立场，是极其专制的，
allowing no debate and imposing exclusions, which are often based on arbitrary premises.
不允许辩论并强加排除，这些排除往往基于武断的前提。
In all this mess, we should always bear in mind that the woke stance and cancel culture are de facto limited to the narrow world of academia
在所有这些混乱中，我们应该始终牢记，觉醒立场和取消文化实际上仅限于狭隘的学术界 （译注：Woke（觉醒）原指对种族不平等和社会不公正问题的觉醒和认识。近年来，其使用范围扩大） （译注：Cancel culture（取消文化）是指一种公众或特定群体因为某个人的言论或行为被视为不当或冒犯性，而采取的一系列行动）
and up to a point some intellectual professions like journalists.
在某种程度上，还有一些知识分子职业，比如记者。
While society at large moves in the opposite direction, cancel culture with its implicit paranoia is a desperate
而社会大众则朝着相反的方向前进，取消文化及其隐含的偏执是一种绝望的、但也是低效的尝试，试图补偿LGBT+个体的实际困境和悲剧，那些他们持续遭受的暴力和排斥。
I'm well aware of this.
我很清楚这一点。
But I think that precisely, cancel culture is a retreat into a cultural fortress,
但我认为，取消文化正是退入到一个文化堡垒中，一种伪安全空间，其话语的狂热保持不变甚至加强了大多数人对它的抵抗。
So you got my point.
所以你明白我的观点了。
I'm not attacking woke and cancel culture as being too fanatical and so on.
我不是在攻击觉醒和取消文化因为它们过于狂热等等。
I claim precisely that behind this mask of fanaticism, stringency, it's a compromise.
我正是声称，在这种狂热、严格的面具背后，实际上是一种妥协。
It doesn't really change social reality.
它并没有真正改变社会现实。
Now on the opposite side, the hidden tension of the conservatives who reject the idea that sexual identity is a discouraged social construct becomes palpable
现在，在另一边，保守派人士隐藏的紧张情绪变得显而易见，他们拒绝承认性别认同是一种不受欢迎的社会建构。
where in the panic with which they reject the project of the LGBT plus education,
他们（保守派，父权制，二元论等）在恐慌中拒绝 LGBT +的教育项目，它应该向孩子展示性身份的所有选择，
they fear that if children are to be educated in this way, they might be influenced to betray their natural sex and choose some unnatural form.
他们担心如果以这种方式教育孩子，他们可能会受到影响，背叛他们的自然性别，选择一些不自然的形式。
This is why recently Russia prohibited all gay and LGBT propaganda.
这就是为什么最近Russia禁止了所有同性恋和LGBT宣传。
In short, I don't know if it happens also in your country, it happens in my country all around Europe now,
简而言之，我不知道这是否也发生在你的国家，它现在发生在我的国家和整个欧洲，
how again, conservatives are horrified by this idea if you teach young children about LGBT construction or sexual identity,
如果你教导年幼的孩子有关 LGBT 建构或性别认同的知识，保守派人士会再次对这个想法感到震惊，
that this may affect them and that they will effectively become gay, trans and so on.
他们认为这可能会影响孩子们，他们实际上会成为同性恋、跨性别者等。
But the paradox is clear here.
但这里的悖论很清楚。
They don't believe their own idea that sex is natural.
他们并不相信自己的观点，即性别是自然的。
If they were to believe it, they wouldn't be so afraid.
如果他们真的相信它，他们就不会如此害怕。
Again, if one's sexual orientation is so easily changed by education, does this not imply that sexual identity is a social construct?
再次，如果一个人的性取向如此容易通过教育改变，这难道不意味着性别身份是一种社会构建吗？
So how to break out of this cycle?
那么如何打破这个循环呢？
Now comes the most problematic part.
现在来到最有问题的部分。
We got an unexpected hint from Ukraine where something happened recently which may appear a step further in our moral decay.
我们从Ukraine得到了一个意想不到的暗示，最近发生了一些事情，看起来似乎会让我们的道德进一步堕落。
But I don't think so.
但我不这么认为。
I think it's the opposite.
我认为恰恰相反。
On October 13th, it was revealed that more than 15,000 Ukrainians have planned to organize a mass orgy in case Putin launches a nuclear attack on Ukraine.
10月13日，有消息透露，超过15,000名Ukraine人计划在普京对Ukraine发动核攻击的情况下组织一次大规模的性派对。
This is not a joke.
这不是玩笑。
I checked it up with my Ukrainian friends.
我向我的Ukraine朋友确认了这一点。
15,000 individuals have registered for this event, which is being called Orgy at Shekavitsa.
15,000个人已经为这一事件注册，这一事件被称为Shekavitsa大乱交。
The mass event will be taking place, okay now it will not, probably there will be no nuclear bomb, will be taking place in a predesided place on a hill in Chekhovitsa, part of Kiev.
这一大规模活动将在基辅的Chekhovitsa的一个山丘上的预定地点举行，好吧现在可能不会有核弹爆炸了。
It was well organized.
它组织得很好。
People participating have been asked to decorate their hands with stripes denoting their sexual preference.
参与者被要求用条纹装饰他们的手，以表示他们的性偏好。
If you want anal sex, you have three stripes on your hand.
如果你想要肛交，你手上有三条纹。
If you are interested in oral sex, you have four stripes and so on.
如果你对口交感兴趣，你手上有四条纹，等等。
The reaction of participants is those who are registered, it's noteworthy.
参与者的反应，那些已经注册的人，值得注意。
One woman told a reporter, it's the opposite of despair. Even in the worst case scenario, people will look for something good.
一位女士告诉记者，这与绝望相反。即使在最坏的情况下，人们也会寻找好的东西。
This is the mega optimism of Ukrainians.
这就是Ukraine人的极度乐观。
And similar groups popped up.
类似的团体也出现了。
For example, an orgy on Deribasivka Street in Odessa and so on.
例如，在敖德萨的德里巴斯夫卡街等地也有类似的聚会。
Now, one should take notion of collective orgy as a life-affirming project in the time of extreme despair.
现在，我们应该将集体性狂欢视为极度绝望时的生命肯定项目。
No need here for a deeper pseudo-Freudian analysis of the disintegration of civilized social links in a traumatic time.
这里不需要对文明社会联系在创伤时期的解体进行更深入的伪弗洛伊德分析。
The truly non-civilized procedure is what Russia is doing, giving its soldiers Viagra to rape Ukrainian women,
真正非文明的做法是Russia正在做的事，给其士兵发放伟哥去强奸Ukraine女性，
UN envoy Pramila Petin reported that rapes and sexual assaults attributed to Moscow's forces were part of Russia's military strategy.
联合国特使普拉米拉·佩廷报告说，莫斯科军队实施的强奸和性侵犯是Russia军事战略的一部分。
That's the true horror for me.
这对我来说是真正的恐怖。
How comes that Russia is doing this?
Russia为何会这么做？
We have to go a little bit deeper.
我们需要更深入地探讨一下。
Simply, the rule is that everything is permitted in the struggle called by Putin and his ideologists – Satanists.
简单地说，规则是在普京和他的思想家认为，在于“撒旦主义者”进行的战争中，一切都是允许的。
The term regularly used in the Russian media has to be taken seriously.
这个在Russia媒体上定期使用的术语需要被严肃对待。
Alexey Pavlov, Assistant Secretary of the Security Council of the Russian Federation,
Russia联邦安全会议的助理秘书阿列克谢·帕夫洛夫，
is now calling for the de-Satanization of Ukraine, saying that there were hundreds of sects in the countries of sects where citizens have abandoned orthodox values.
现在呼吁对Ukraine进行去撒旦化，他说，这些国家有数百个教派，公民放弃了东正教价值观。
I believe that with the continuation of our special military operation, it becomes more and more urgent to carry out the de-Satanisation of Ukraine.
我相信，随着我们特别军事行动的继续，进行Ukraine去撒旦化变得越来越迫切。
The new regime turned Ukraine from a sovereign state to a totalitarian hyper sect.
新政权将Ukraine从一个主权国家变成了一个极权主义的超级教派。
Putin echoes the same stance, quote from Putin.
普京呼应了同样的立场，引用普京的话。
This is a complete denial of humanity, the overthrow of faith and traditional values.
这是对人性的彻底否定，是对信仰和传统价值观的颠覆。
Indeed, the suppression of freedom itself has taken on the features of a religion, outright Satanism."
的确，压制自由本身已经呈现出一种宗教的特征，彻头彻尾的撒旦教。
No wonder that Patriarch Kirill, the head of the Russian Orthodox Church, called Putin a fighter against the Antichrist and chief exorcist.
难怪Russia东正教教会的头目基里尔大牧首称普京为反基督的战士和首席驱魔师。
Some people ask how Russia, still a normal state, can ally itself with fundamentalist Iran.
有些人问，Russia仍然是一个正常的国家，怎么会与原教旨主义的伊朗结盟。
But we can see now that, if anything, Russia is more fundamentalist than Iran.
但我们现在可以看到，如果有什么的话，Russia比伊朗更加原教旨主义。
Now I raise my stakes and make us go a step further.
现在让我们更进一步。
What is, I think, even more morbid than Russia's brutality and this open ideology of fighting You know that now the goal, again, this is not official discourse in Russia.
我认为，比Russia的残暴和这种公开的战斗意识形态更为病态的是，你知道现在的目标，再次，这不是Russia的官方话语。
It's no longer denazify Ukraine, but de-Satanize.
不再是对Ukraine去纳粹化，而是去撒旦化。
What is even more morbid for me are some leftists,
对我来说更病态的是一些左派，
personics working for peace, who claim that now is the time to send a big European delegation to Russia to inquire and negotiate about the terms of peace.
为和平工作的人士，他们声称现在是时候向Russia派遣一个大型的欧洲代表团去询问和谈判和平条款。
Please, my comment.
请听我的评论。
I hope you all know the well-known joke evoked by Freud on the borrowed kettle.
我希望你们都知道弗洛伊德提到的那个关于借来的水壶的著名笑话。
First, let's say I borrow a kettle from you.
首先，假设我向你借了一头水壶。
I return it to you broken.
我把它还给你时，它已经坏了。
And then you said, what, it's broken?
然后你说，什么，它坏了？
And my defense is, first, I never borrowed a kettle from you, second, I return it to you unbroken.
我的辩护是，首先，我从未向你借过水壶，第二，我还给你时它是好的。
Third, the kettle was already broken when I got it from you.
第三，当我从你那里得到它时，水壶已经坏了。
Do those who oppose hectic Ukraine with arms not fall prey to a similar paradox?
那些用武器反对Ukraine的人难道不是陷入了类似的悖论吗？
Their arguments clearly fall into three categories.
他们的论点明显分为三类。
First, abstract superego reasoning. Giving arms never stops the war. It's like pouring oil on fire. So it's always immoral and murderous.
首先，抽象超我推理。提供武器永远不会停止战争。这就像火上浇油。所以它总是不道德和谋杀性的。
That's the abstract position.
那是抽象的立场。
Then you have a more concrete listing of particular arguments.
然后你有更具体的列出特定论点。
Okay, Russia committed a horrible crime by invading another state, but Ukraine is also not innocent, so we cannot put the blame only on one side and so on and so on.
好吧，Russia侵入另一个国家犯下了可怕的罪行，但Ukraine也不是无辜的，所以我们不能只怪罪于一方等等。
And third, more and more popular in Europe and in United States, direct egotism.
第三，在欧洲和美国越来越受欢迎的直接自私自利。
Why getting involved in a war far away which will only hurt our interests and living standards?
为什么要卷入一场远离我们、只会伤害我们利益和生活水平的战争？
And let me make another argument against pacifism.
让我再提出一个反和平主义的论点。
Yes, of course, my God, I'm scared like shit of nuclear war.
是的，当然了，我的天，我非常害怕核战争。
But at the same time, don't forget that all occupiers are sincerely always for peace.
但同时，不要忘记所有占领者都真诚地永远支持和平。
Peace means I want peace in the occupied territory, leave me alone.
和平意味着我想要在被占领领土上的和平，别打扰我。
Germany, when they occupied France in 1940, of course they wanted peace there.
德国1940年占领法国时，当然他们希望那里和平。
Israel on the West Bank, West Bank is a special case.
以色列在西岸，西岸是一个特殊情况。
I oppose terrorist attacks from Gaza or South Lebanon, but on the West Bank, of course Israel want peace, because peace means doing our job, gradual ethnic cleansing of it.
我反对来自加沙或南黎巴嫩的恐怖袭击，但在西岸，以色列当然希望和平，因为和平意味着完成我们的任务，逐步的种族清洗。
The Pisanics, who are against NATO and sending arms to Ukraine, ignore the key fact that it was Western help that allowed Ukraine to resist.
反对北约和向Ukraine发送武器的和平主义者忽略了一个关键事实，即是西方的帮助使Ukraine得以抵抗，没有它，Ukraine早就被占领了。
This help led to today's stalemate which maybe now created conditions for a possible compromise.
这种帮助导致了今天的僵局，这也许为可能的妥协创造了条件。
So in Germany, I admire the stance of the Green Party, which not only advocates support
所以在德国，我钦佩绿党的立场，它不仅提倡支持Ukraine，而且还提出利用当前的石油和天然气危机作为一个独特的机会，使我们的工业更加绿色。
You see, I like this stance.
你看，我喜欢这个立场。
Most of us, for most of us, the problem is just, OK, it's dramatic, we should help them, but not too much.
对我们大多数人来说，问题只是，好吧，这很戏剧性，我们应该帮助他们，但不要太多。
How will it disturb our way of life?
它将如何扰乱我们的生活方式？
We are used to live in a comfortable way.
我们习惯了舒适的生活方式。
Is it not a much better position to say, but why don't we use this situation to make our industry is greener for an ecological turn and so on and so on.
难道不是一个更好的立场么，即说，但为什么我们不利用这种情况使我们的工业更加绿色，为了生态转型等等。
Did you notice another inconsistency in those who want direct peace, which basically means put pressure on Ukraine to give one-third of their land to Russia?
你有没有注意到那些想要直接和平的人中的另一个不一致性，这基本上意味着向Ukraine施压，想让他们将三分之一的土地给予Russia？
They first insisted that Ukraine simply cannot win a war against Russia.
他们首先坚持认为Ukraine根本无法赢得对Russia的战争。
Chomsky, Varoufakis, they were all saying this, let's be realist.
乔姆斯基、瓦鲁法基斯，他们都这么说，让我们现实一点，Ukraine无法赢。
But now, when, at least for a moment, it's not yet over,
但现在，至少暂时，还没有结束，Ukraine正在赢得战争，
they repeat that it shouldn't be allowed to win or even to gain too much because this may provoke Putin's ire and he may press the button.
他们重申，不应该允许它获胜，甚至不应该让它获得太多，因为这可能会激起普京的愤怒，他可能会按下按钮。
Now, what is the truth behind it?
现在，这背后的真相是什么？
Recall how in the first days of the war, Western powers offered Zelensky, Ukrainian president,
回想一下战争初期，西方国家提供给泽连斯基，Ukraine总统，就在战争开始的两三天内，
you remember, just two, three days into it, they offered him a special plane to take him out of Kiev, implying that the situation is already lost, so let's get over it fast.
他们提供了一架特别飞机将他带出基辅，暗示情况已经失控，所以让我们快点结束它。
This hysterical precipitous offer made palpable the true desire of the West,
这种仓促的歇斯底里的提议显露了西方的真正欲望，
a desire which was spoiled by the unexpected Ukrainian resistance.
一种因Ukraine出乎意料的抵抗而受挫的欲望。
That's for me the truth.
对我来说这就是真相。
I wonder if you agree with it.
我想知道你是否同意。
And I have many friends that, we in the West, all my political friends in Slovenia, in France,
我有许多朋友，在西方，我所有的政治朋友在斯洛文尼亚、在法国，
I could feel the secret pleasure when, you know, in the first day there were already Russian commandos dropped onto Kiev.
我能感觉到当你知道，在第一天Russia突击队就已经空降到基辅时他们的秘密愉悦。
They thought, okay, okay, it will be soon over, then we will protest, but it will be over.
他们认为，好吧，好吧，很快就会结束，然后我们会抗议，但它会结束。
The true best surprise was Ukrainians really, they tell you this privately, not publicly, Ukrainians screwed up everything by their resistance.
真正最大的惊喜是Ukraine人真的，（他们私下里告诉你，不是公开地），Ukraine人通过他们的抵抗搞砸了一切。
Couldn't they just swallow it and sacrifice themselves for our Western welfare and so on?
他们难道就不能忍受一下，为了我们西方的福祉牺牲自己吗？
So now our obsession is let's make peace, but peace in such a way that Russia should be allowed to save face.
所以现在我们的困扰是让我们和平，但和平要以这样一种方式，Russia应该被允许保全面子。
What does this mean?
这意味着什么？
Dmitry Medvedev, a former Russian president who now serves as deputy chairman of Russia's Security Council
德米特里·梅德韦杰夫，Russia前总统，现任Russia安全委员会副主席
recently said that the US-led NATO military alliance would be too scared of a nuclear apocalypse to directly enter the conflict in response to Russia using tactical nuclear weapons.
最近表示，由美国领导的北约军事联盟因为害怕核末日而不敢直接介入冲突，以应对Russia使用战术核武器的情况。
I believe that NATO will not directly intervene in the conflict even in this situation.
我相信即使在这种情况下，北约也不会直接介入冲突。
After all, the security of Washington, London, Brussels is much more important for the North Atlantic alliance than the fate of a dying Ukraine that no one needs.
毕竟，对北大西洋联盟而言，华盛顿、伦敦、布鲁塞尔的安全远比一个没人需要的垂死的Ukraine的命运重要得多。
The supply of modern weapons is just a business for Western countries.
现代武器的供应对于西方国家来说只是一桩生意。
Overseas and European demagogues are not going to perish in a nuclear apocalypse, therefore Therefore, they will swallow the use of any weapon in the current conflict.
海外和欧洲的煽动者不想在核灾难中灭亡，因此，他们将在当前冲突中放弃使用任何武器。
You see, that's why for me this idea, let's allow Putin to save his face, doesn't work.
你看，这就是为什么对我来说，让普京保全面子的想法行不通。
Because what Medvedev says here is exact what amounts to preventing the West to save its face.
因为梅德韦杰夫在这里所说的正是阻止西方保全面子的事。
Medvedev in advance interprets every compromise as the West will lose its face, they are afraid,
梅德韦杰夫预先解释说，任何妥协都会让西方失去面子，他们害怕，他们不想在核战争中灭亡等等。
Also, as for the background of the war, and I'm talking now as a Leninist communist my Here you get, please listen carefully and then we will slowly come to the end, Putin.
至于战争的背景，现在我以列宁主义communism者的身份讲话，请仔细听，然后我们将慢慢结束，普京。
Putin, it's incredible, people forgot this what Putin said on 21st of February, two days before the attack.
普京，这令人难以置信，人们忘记了普京在2月21日，攻击前两天说的话。
I found these lines shocking.
我发现这些话令人震惊。
I don't get it how some leftists claim NATO imperialism and so
我不明白一些左派是如何声称北约帝国主义等等的
Putin openly declares himself conservative with a goal to destroy European unity.
普京公开宣称自己是保守主义者，目标是破坏欧洲的团结。
He's systematically supporting all extreme right-wing in Europe, Le Pen in France, Salvini in Italy, and so on and so on.
他系统地支持欧洲所有极右翼分子，法国的勒庞，意大利的萨尔维尼，等等。
And the big bad guy for him is Lenin.
对他来说，大坏蛋是列宁。
And it's true, look at the history.
这是真的，看看历史。
The 20s, okay, there was a civil war, blah, blah, but in 22 or when the civil war was over, it was a golden era for Ukraine.
20年代，好吧，那时有内战，等等，但在22年或内战结束时，那是Ukraine的黄金时代。
Under Tsarist Russia, Ukrainian language was not recognized and so on and so on.
在沙皇俄国时期，Ukraine语没有得到承认等等。
In the 20s, Ukraine was admitted as a full nation with all the cultural apparatus.
20年代，Ukraine作为一个拥有完整文化体系的完整民族被接纳。
It was an extraordinary time, especially in Ukraine.
那是一个特别的时期，特别是在Ukraine。
Like, do you know that for some time, there were its incredible story, just the visual arts.
比如，你知道吗，有一段时间，有一个令人难以置信的故事，就是视觉艺术。
At some college in Ukraine, College of Visual Arts, At the same time, Malevich and Chagall were teaching.
在Ukraine的某个视觉艺术学院，那个时候，马列维奇和夏加尔同时在教书。
They couldn't stand each other and so on.
他们彼此无法忍受等等。(译注：Russia前卫艺术家，被认为是抽象艺术运动和特别是绝对主义（Suprematism）的先驱；夏加尔是一位白Russia-法国艺术家，以他充满幻想的作品和对颜色的独特运用而闻名)
It was a golden era.
那是一个黄金时代。
Then, with Stalin, the line changed, which is why today in Russia,
然后，在Stalinist时代，路线发生了变化，这就是为什么今天在Russia，列宁出局，Stalinist半进局。
And also, this idea of, this is the most dangerous line of argumentation, I don't know if you have it here, this idea of Euro-Asianism.
还有，这种观点，这是最危险的论证路线，我不知道你们这里是否有这种观点，就是欧亚主义的想法。
My God, do people know history?
我的天，人们知道历史吗？
At the origin, this is a fascist idea.
这一思想起源，本质上是一个法西斯主义的想法。
Do you know that already in the early 20s, among Russian immigration, anti-communist immigration,
你知道吗，早在20年代初，Russia的反共移民中，
came this idea that, for example, the main person here is Ivan Ilyin,
就出现了这样的想法，例如，这里的主要人物是伊凡·伊林，
who is now quasi-official philosopher.
他现在几乎是官方哲学家。
His body was transported from France, brought to Russia, buried with all state owners, and so on and so on.
他的遗体从法国运回Russia，带有所有国家的荣誉安葬等等。
His idea was that fascism was good.
他的观点是法西斯主义是好的。
He supported to the end Mussolini, Hitler, the West, and Hitler.
他支持到底墨索里尼、希特勒、西方和希特勒。
But that their fascism was too much under the influence of Western mechanical society to industrial.
但他们的法西斯主义过于受到西方机械社会的影响，过于工业化。
And that the only true fascism would have been the Russian fascism as the right balance
而唯一真正的法西斯主义将是Russia法西斯主义，
between Western individualism and aging this global immersion of the individual into a crowd and so on and so on.
作为西方个人主义和东方这种个体全然融入群体等等之间的正确平衡。
Here I am.
现在我来得出我的结论。
What interests me, and this is the real danger that I see,
我感兴趣的是，这是我所看到的真正危险，
is that this Putin's line of criticizing the West as decadent, orgy, and so on, gay rights, LGBT plus, is more and more
普京批评西方堕落、性放纵等，关于同性恋权利、LGBT+的言论越来越多
in consonance with American new right.
与美国新右翼相呼应。
My, I use this term with full irony, friend Jordan Peterson from the debate.
我用这个词完全是带有讽刺意味的，我的“朋友”乔丹·彼得森从辩论中。
I was shocked.
我很震惊。
I didn't know he will do this.
我不知道他会这么做。
You know that he adopted now pro-Russian position.
你知道，他现在采取了亲俄立场。
But I think in some sense he is right, not in the sense that I agree with him.
但我认为在某种意义上他是对的，不是说我同意他。
But I think that Americans knew religious conservatism and what Putin is doing are gradually getting coordinated.
但我认为美国的新宗教保守主义和普京所做的事情逐渐正在协调一致。
The Republican Party lawmakers who oppose support for Ukraine are getting stronger and stronger.
反对为Ukraine提供支持的共和党议员越来越强大。
They do not want to send money abroad when it can be used in the U.S. to fortify the southern border and so on.
他们不想将钱送到国外，而是可以在美国用于加强南部边境等。
For example, Trump-backed candidate P.D. Vance criticized Ukraine as a corrupt nation run by oligarchs, and while he formally condemned Russia's invasion,
例如，特朗普支持的候选人P.D. Vance批评Ukraine是一个由寡头运营的腐败国家，尽管他正式谴责了Russia的入侵，
he also called it insulting and strategically stupid to devote billions of resources to Ukraine while ignoring the problems in our own countries.
他还称将数十亿资源投入到Ukraine，同时忽略我们自己国家的问题，是侮辱性的和战略上的愚蠢。
So, a Russian attack on Ukraine and the alt-right revolt in the US are two aspects of the same global movement.
因此，对Ukraine的Russia攻击和美国的另类右翼叛乱是同一全球运动的两个方面。
If the Western Christian revolt and the Russian anti-European stance will unite into one, This will be a global sociopolitical catastrophe of immeasurable amplitude.
如果西方基督教的反叛和Russia反欧洲立场联合起来，这将是一场不可估量的全球社会政治灾难。
For the US and Russia, Russian neoconservatives, Europe is caught in the vortex of self-destructive the generation, LGBT+, gay marriages, no clear distinction of sexes.
对于美国和Russia，Russia新保守主义者来说，欧洲陷入了自我毁灭的退化漩涡，LGBT+、同性婚姻、性别界限不明确。
So one cannot but note the obvious imminent inconsistency of the neo-conservatives from the Russian ones to American alt-right
因此，人们不得不注意到从Russia新保守主义者到美国另类右翼的明显即将出现的不一致性
while they pretend to deplore the multicultural hedonism, and present themselves as the embodiment of traditional Christian values,
虽然他们假装哀叹多元文化的享乐主义，并将自己呈现为传统基督教价值观的化身，
their works and acts display extraordinary vulgarity, sexism and racism.
他们的言行却展现出非凡的粗俗、性别歧视和种族主义。
Let me just conclude with one case.
让我以一个案例结束。
You remember, it occurred back in 2012.
你们记得，这发生在2012年。
In an effort to explain his stance on abortion, Rep. Todd Akin, the Republican Senate nominee from Missouri,
密苏里州的共和党参议院候选人托德·阿金（Todd Akin）在解释他对堕胎立场的努力中，
provoked Ayer across the political spectrum by saying that in instances of what he called legitimate rape, women's bodies somehow block an unwanted pregnancy.
他说在他所谓的合法强奸情况下，女性的身体以某种方式阻止了不想要的怀孕，这一说法激起了政治光谱上的愤怒。
Responding to this theory, Akin claimed that he has misspoken, he really wanted to say that there are legitimate cases of rape where penetration is really enforced.
针对这一理论，阿金声称自己说错了，他真的想说，存在合法的强奸案件，但真正实施了插入。
But that if the victim shows signs of consent, say getting wet and excited, this then is no longer a legitimate case of rape.
但如果受害者显示出同意的迹象，比如变湿和兴奋，那么这就不再是合法的强奸案例了。
I think this confusion reveals the truth.
我认为这种混淆揭示了真相。
What Akin really wanted to say is precisely what his misspoken formulation says.
阿金真正想要说的正是他失言所表达的。
In some cases, rape is legitimate since the victim showed signs of participation, which means it really wasn't rape.
即，在某些情况下，强奸是合法的，因为受害者显示出了参与的迹象，这意味着它实际上不是强奸。
Leaving behind the obvious falsity and vulgarities of Aikin's reasoning, I want to draw the parallel with the Russian attack on Ukraine since the matter of rape was also evoked from the Russian side.
撇开阿金推理的明显虚假和粗俗不谈，我想将此与Russia对Ukraine的攻击相提并论，因为Russia方面也提到了强奸问题。
At a press conference on February 7th, Putin noted that the Ukrainian government does not like the means agreement and then add it.
在2月7日的新闻发布会上，普京指出Ukraine政府不喜欢明斯克协议，然后补充说。
Like it or not, it's your duty, my beauty.
不管喜不喜欢，这是你的责任，我的美人。
The saying has well-known sexual connotations.
这句话有众所周知的性暗示。
Putin quoted, was quoting from Sleeping Beauty in a Coffin,
普京引用的是《睡美人在棺材里》，
sung by a Soviet era punk group, Red Mold, where you have the lines,
这是苏联时代朋克乐队红霉素（Red Mold）的一首歌，其中有这样的歌词，
sleeping beauty in a coffin, I crept up and fucked her, like it or dislike it, sleep my beauty.
睡美人在棺材里，我悄悄上前和她做爱，喜欢也罢，不喜欢也罢，睡吧，我的美人。
So there is a clear reference to rape here.
所以这里明确地提到了强奸。
There are cases when the rape of a country is legitimate,
有些情况下，对一个国家的强奸是合法的，
that is to say, justified.
也就是说，是有理由的。
My point is that such male chauvinist obscenities are the not even so hidden truth of the proponents of traditional Christian values.
我的观点是，这种男性沙文主义的猥亵事实是那些提倡传统基督教价值观者的不那么隐藏的真相。
So again, to really conclude,
所以，再次，真正地总结，
we should accept Peterson's basic premise.
我们应该接受彼得森的基本前提。
Russian attack on Ukraine and the alt-right revolt in the US are two aspects of the same global movement.
Russia对Ukraine的攻击和美国另类右翼的叛乱是同一全球运动的两个方面。
But does this mean that in contrast to him, to Peterson, we should support the opposite side?
但这是否意味着与彼得森相反，我们应该支持对立面？
Here things get complicated.
这里的事情变得复杂了。
It is true that if the Western Christian revolt and the Russian anti-European stance will unite into one, this will be a global catastrophe.
诚然，如果西方基督教的反抗和Russia的反欧洲立场合而为一，这将是一场全球性的灾难。
However, we are still dealing with an antagonism internal to global capitalism.
然而，我们仍在应对全球资本主义内部的对抗。
What Peterson attacks is the ultimate consequence of global capitalism itself.
彼得森攻击的是全球资本主义本身的最终后果。
We all know the most famous line from Marxist communist manifesto.
我们都知道Marx主义communism宣言中最著名的一句话。
The bourgeoisie, wherever it has got the upper hand, has put an end to all feudal patriarchal idyllic relations.
资产阶级只要一得势，就把一切从中世纪承传下来的、用来保障整个社会秩序的封建或宗法的关系全都破坏掉。
All that is solid melts into air, all that is holy is profaned, and man is at least compelled to face with sober senses his real conditions of life."
一切稳定的东西都烟消云散，一切圣洁的东西都被亵渎，人终于不得不用冷静的眼光来看他的生活地位，他的相互关系。
I think that what is still ignored, this is still ignored by those leftist cultural theorists who focus their critique on patriarchal ideology and practice.
我认为，那些将批判焦点放在父权意识形态和实践上的左翼文化理论家仍然忽视了这一点。
Is it not time to start to wonder about the fact that the critique of patriarchy was elevated into the main target at the very historical moment,
难道现在不是时候开始思考这样一个事实：在父权制明显失去霸权地位的历史时刻，批判父权制被提升为主要目标吗？
What becomes of patriarchal family values when a child can sue his parents for neglect and abuse?
当一个孩子可以因为忽视和虐待起诉他的父母时，父权家庭价值观变成了什么？
When family and parenthood are reduced to temporally dissolvable contract between independent individuals.
当家庭和父母职责被降低为独立个体之间的可解除的临时合约时。
So the culture war raging in the developed west now, in the States, in Europe, is I think a false war, a war between two versions of the same global capitalist system.
所以，现在在发达西方国家，如美国、欧洲正在肆虐的文化战争，我认为是一场假战争，是同一全球资本主义系统的两个版本之间的战争。
It unrestrained pure version, which is this insistence on infinite dynamics, plasticity,
它的无限动态、可塑性不受限制的纯粹版本，LGBT，不断重塑你的身份，以及它的新法西斯保守主义版本，试图将资本主义动力与更传统的价值观结合起来。
The paradox is here double.
这里的悖论是双重的。
The Western political correctness is a displacement of the good old class struggle.
西方的政治正确性取代了古老的阶级斗争。
The liberal elite pretends to protect the threatened racial and sexual minorities in order to obfuscate the basic fact of their privileged economic and power position.
自由派精英假装保护受到威胁的种族和性少数群体，以掩盖他们特权的经济和权力地位的基本事实。
And this lie allows the alt-right populists to present themselves as a defense of the real working class against the big corporations and the deep state elites.
这个谎言让另类右翼民粹主义者能够将自己呈现为真正的工人阶级对抗大公司和深州精英的保护者。
The paradox is thus that today's populist conservatives are more revolutionary than and the politically correct liberals
悖论在于，今天的民粹保守主义者比政治正确的自由主义者更具革命性，
who are not afraid to call for social order and even police oppression when they feel this is needed.
当他们觉得有必要时，他们不害怕召唤社会秩序，甚至是警察镇压。
We often hear the complaint, where were the police and National Guard on January 6, 2021.
我们经常听到的抱怨是，2021年1月6日那天，警察和国民警卫队在哪里。
The implication to be drawn is not just that left and right are today outdated notions, But that both poles of today's Cold War can only be properly grasped as a displaced class struggle.
所要引出的含义不仅是“左”和“右”在今天已经过时了，而且还表明，当今冷战的两极只能被正确地理解为一场流离失所的阶级斗争。
Neither of them really stands for those exploited.
它们都不真正代表那些被剥削者。
And again, this is our tragic predicament today.
再次，这是我们今天的悲剧性困境。
You remember, I was, of course, my eyes were glued to the screen on January 6th of the previous year.
你记得，我当然是，去年1月6日我的眼睛被屏幕吸引住了。
You remember the crowd invading capital.
你记得人群闯入首都。
But what shocked me so much is how many of my leftist friends in the United States and in Europe were crying.
但让我非常震惊的是，我的许多左翼朋友在美国和欧洲都在哭泣。
They said, what is going on?
他们说，发生了什么？
We the people should be doing this.
做这件事的应该是我们的人民。
It's beautiful to watch it, but the wrong guys are doing it.
这件事看着很美，但正在做这件事的是错误的人。
That's our predicament today.
这就是我们今天的困境。
I think what, again, I listen, I even sometimes listen to Steve Bannon's podcasts or whatever.
我认为，再次，我听，我有时甚至听史蒂夫·班农的播客或者其他。
And did you notice how he's doing almost the same thing as Putin?
你有没有注意到他几乎在做和普京一样的事情？
He begins like if he has a one-hour podcast talk with the first 20 minutes, I almost fully agree.
他开始时如果他有一个小时的播客谈话，前20分钟我几乎完全同意。
He describes how the big corporations stayed, employs ordinary blah blah blah, all that.
他描述了大公司、国家如何剥削普通人，等等。
Then, of course, things take a strange turn.
然后，当然，事情开始变得奇怪。
It's the same I heard from my friends in Moscow who are like with one leg in prison already but with the other leg still running around, that Putin is doing the same.
同样的，我从我的莫斯科朋友那里听到，他们一只脚已经在监狱里，但另一只脚还在外面跑，普京在做同样的事情。
He doesn't have only Dugin and this religious orthodox maniac.
他不仅仅有杜金和这个宗教正统狂热分子。
Putin also mobilized a group of young Marxists who are providing him a more leftist Third World line.
普京还动员了一群年轻的Marx主义者，他们为他提供了一个更左翼的第三世界路线。
They provided him with this line, Russia is really defending the world from Western imperialist colonization.
他们为他提供了这样的路线，Russia真的在保护世界免受西方帝国主义殖民。
We are on the side of all those exploited in the Third World and so on and so on.
我们站在所有在第三世界被剥削者的一边，等等。
And I hope you are aware of this situation, how incredibly successful this Russian propaganda is
我希望你们意识到这种情况，Russia的宣传是如何在拉丁美洲、亚洲的许多地区、非洲等地取得了难以置信的成功。
So, I think that maybe this is the crucial dilemma today.
所以，我认为这可能是今天的关键困境。
Our situation today is the one of crisis of a system itself.
我们今天的处境是系统本身的危机。
What conservatives got right is that this Fukuyama ideal of liberal democratic capitalism is in full crisis, in the sense of, you know what is for me the most ominous case?
保守派认识到的是，这个福山式的自由民主资本主义理想正处于全面危机之中，你知道对我来说最不祥的案例是什么吗？
In England, in France, in United States, you have now protests which are no longer like in some parts of Eastern Europe, protests for true democracy.
在英格兰、法国、美国，现在有抗议活动，这些活动不再像东欧某些地区那样，是为了真正的民主。
No, they they articulate a doubt in our version of liberal democracy itself. And the tragedy is that there is no way to to give to articulate in organized political way this rage.
不，他们对我们当前版本的自由民主本身表达了怀疑。悲剧在于，没有办法以有组织的政治方式表达这种愤怒。
And with this I want to To conclude, we are back at the beginning of European history.
我想以此结束，我们回到了欧洲历史的开始。
My friend, although a right-winger, he is not stupid, Peter Sloterdijk, wrote a wonderful book, Being and Rage, Sein und Zorren,
我的朋友，虽然是右翼人士，但他并不愚蠢，彼得·斯洛特代克写了一本精彩的书，《存在与愤怒》（Sein und Zorren），
of course an ironic paraphrase of Heidegger's Being in Time, where he said, what's at the beginning, at least in our mythic view of the western culture, it's Homer Iliad.
当然是对海德格尔的《存在与时间》的讽刺性改编，他说，至少在我们对西方文化的神话观中，一切都始于荷马的《伊利亚特》。
And what is the first line of Iliad, a call to the dead goddess, whatever, to allow him to do a poem on the rage of Achilles, which brought blah, blah, blah.
《伊利亚特》的第一行是向死去的女神（或其他什么）的呼唤，让他能够写一首关于阿喀琉斯的愤怒的诗，这愤怒带来了种种后果，等等。
Today we have even a much more dangerous rage, dissatisfaction.
今天，我们面临着一种更加危险的愤怒，不满的行动，而真正悲剧的是，左翼正在失去这种愤怒。
I think that – I agree here with the guy whom I criticised briefly, Varoufakis – I think that capitalism is changing already into something different.
我认为——在这一点上我同意我之前简要批评过的瓦鲁法基斯——我认为资本主义已经在变成某种不同的东西。
And either we will invent – I don't like to use the word communism, it's too crazy but a really new social order to deal with the ongoing problems,
要么我们将发明——我不喜欢使用communism这个词，它太疯狂了，但一个真正新的社会秩序来解决正在进行的问题，
or a new form of fascism, sorry, of neo-federalism, let's call it, will take over.
要么一种新形式的法西斯主义，抱歉，让我们称之为新联邦主义，将会接管。
So, you know, what, again, what I would be really my nightmare is and Trump is already sending signals and so on,
所以，你知道，再次，真正成为我的噩梦的是，特朗普已经在发出信号等等，
even Bolsonaro is more friendly towards Putin and so on.
甚至博尔索纳罗对普京更加友好等等。
This pact between European and whatever new populist conservatives and Russia and so on,
这种欧洲和任何新的民粹保守主义者与Russia等的联盟，
that's the danger.
那是危险所在。
And I don't think we are taking seriously this danger because we too much still believe in liberal democracy.
我认为我们没有认真对待这种危险，因为我们仍然过于相信自由民主。
I appreciate liberal democracy.
我欣赏自由民主。
It's a wonderful thing, but today it's a crisis.
这是一件美好的事情，但今天它正处于危机之中。
Because the only way to confront all the problems we have today is to make a step beyond.
因为对抗我们今天所面临的所有问题的唯一方法是向前迈出一步。
And that's the reason of my pessimism.
这就是我悲观的原因。
You know why?
你知道为什么吗？
To conclude, I don't, you know, in good old Marxist, all liberal times, we still could rely on historical faith necessity, like this Marxist faith of history is moving towards progress and so on.
总而言之，我不知道，在古老的Marx主义、所有自由主义时代，我们仍然可以依赖历史信仰的必然性，比如Marx主义对历史的信仰正在走向进步等等。
No.
不。
Now we have to act against history.
现在我们必须逆历史而行。
Historical tendency is towards catastrophe.
历史的趋势是走向灾难。
What will happen, I don't know.
会发生什么，我不知道。
But I prefer to be a pessimist in order to awaken us.
但我宁愿做一个悲观主义者，以唤醒我们。
Sorry if I was too long.
抱歉我讲得太长了。
So stop, please, we don't have time for this.
所以请停下，我们没有时间了。
I said some things which may be very problematic for you.
我说了一些对你们可能非常有问题的事情。
First about, I'm not bluffing, you know, I'm not reading a proper Russian propaganda.
首先，我不是在虚张声势，你知道，我不是墨守成规，不是在这里朗读一份Russia的宣传报，以让你们取笑，以展示我堕落有多深
When I was in high school in mid-60s in Slovenia, English was obligatory, first, second language,
当我在60年代中期在斯洛文尼亚的高中时，英语是强制的第一、第二语言，
and then we had the choice of another.
然后我们可以选择另一门。
It was either French or German or Russian.
要么是法语、德语或俄语。
I've chosen Russian for disgusting reasons.
我选择了俄语，出于令人厌恶的原因。
My idea was, it's a cold war, one side will win, I want to be sure to speak the language of the winner.
我的想法是，冷战时期，一方会胜出，我想确保自己能说胜利者的语言。
But now it comes good because you know I am not, I am not just reading about it.
但现在它变得有用了，因为你知道我不仅仅是读到它。
I listen all the time to Russian media
我一直在听Russia媒体
and it's even more horrible than this report.
情况比这个报道还要糟糕。
And the second thing with this I really conclude,
第二件事（我真的要结束了），
some pragmatic friends of mine are telling me but don't take all this stuff about Russian mission, holy war, Don't take it seriously, these are just words.
我的一些务实的朋友告诉我，不要把所有这些关于Russia使命、圣战的东西当真，这些只是话语。
What they really want is just a small part of Ukraine.
他们真正想要的只是Ukraine的一小部分。
No.
不。
Words, if we have something to learn, is that words are not, never only words.
如果我们有什么要学习的，那就是话语从来都不仅仅是话语。
Take the case, I'm not comparing nonetheless Putin with Hitler, but take the case of Germany.
以德国为例，我并不是在将普京与希特勒相比，但请看德国的案例。
Do you know that when Hitler took power in 1933, this was the predominant attitude and Fortunately, among the Jews there, he just needs this rhetoric to take power once he will establish make a deal with him.
你知道吗，当希特勒在1933年掌权时，这是当时犹太人中的主流态度，即，认为他只是需要这种言辞来掌权，一旦他建立了权力，（犹太人）就可以和他达成协议。
No. Words matter.
不。话语很重要。
So I don't believe in this Putin is just saying this or his ideologies in reality.
所以我不相信普京只是在口头上说这些话，不认为他的意识形态是实用主义的。
No. Wars are never simply pragmatic.
不。战争从来都不仅仅是实用的。
You always, how should I put it, get caught into your own words.
你总是，我应该怎么说，被自己的话语捕获。
So, please counter-attack, I would like to hear your counter-opinion, or I hope I made my position clear about LGBT plus and so on, all that.
所以，请反击，我想听听你的反意见，或我希望我已经清楚地表达了我的立场关于LGBT+等等，所有这一切。
I totally support them.
我完全支持他们。
In my country, I also here and there fight for them, with them, and so on.
在我的国家，我也在这里和那里为他们而战，与他们一起，等等。
I'm just saying that the ideology, which not always,
我只是说意识形态并不总是如此
but sometimes accompanies LGBT plus, this simple reliance of the choice of our sex is our free decision and then this game of plasticity, you know, in the sense of,
但有时伴随LGBT+出现，即，这种对性别选择的简单依赖是我们的自由决定，然后这个可塑性的游戏，你知道，从某种意义上说，
oh that's the true freedom. Today I'm gay, tomorrow I'm hetero, next day I'm bisexual, This is so discriminatory and humiliating for LGBT people themselves.
哦，这才是真正的自由。今天我是同性恋，明天我是异性恋，后天我是双性恋，这对 LGBT 人群本身来说是一种极大的歧视和羞辱。
You know how traumatic, for example, I know an example, there was a movie made in Belgium where a boy wanted to become a lady.
你知道，例如，我知道一个例子，比利时拍摄了一部电影，一个男孩想要变成女人。
And it was so traumatic for him, although he or she had the support from parents, everybody was good and so on.
对他来说是如此的创伤，尽管他或她得到了父母的支持，每个人都很好，等等。
And of course, in some sense, it's a choice.
当然，在某种意义上，这是一种选择。
It's not biologically determined.
它不是生物学上决定的。
But it's not a simple conscious choice in the sense of oh, that's how I feel now and so on and so on.
但它不是一个简单的有意识的选择，就像哦，这就是我现在的感觉，等等。
You know that if you are a trans, if you do the operation,
你知道，如果你是跨性别者，如果你进行了手术，
you know how painful are these operations?
你知道这些手术有多痛苦吗？
This is traumatic.
这是创伤性的。
This means you feel the urge to do it.
这意味着你感到迫切需要这样做。
Which means of course it's your choice, but not a simple choice in the sense, oh my God, look, I like boys, I like girls, I like trans people, let's play all of them.
这意味着当然这是你的选择，但不是一个简单的选择，就像，哦天哪，看，我喜欢男孩，我喜欢女孩，我喜欢跨性别者，让我们尝试所有这些。
And you are ready to stake your survival on it.
你准备为此冒生命危险。
So that's what I'm pleading here for.
所以这就是我在这里所恳求的。
It's not biology, but it's also not this superficial how I feel I declare and so on and so on.
这不是生物学，但它也不是这种表面上的我如何感觉我宣布等等。
Do you know that yes, LGBT plus people are free, but they are maybe the most free people among us and they pay the price for it.
你知道吗，是的，LGBT+人群是自由的，但他们可能是我们中间最自由的人，他们为此付出了代价。
You know that here I accept this paradox of true freedom is not this superficial freedom of choice.
你知道，我接受这个悖论，真正的自由不是这种表面上的选择自由。
Like let's go to a patisserie, should be cheesecake or chocolate cake or strawberry cake.
就像去糕点店，是选择芝士蛋糕、巧克力蛋糕还是草莓蛋糕。
True freedom is experienced usually even as necessity.
真正的自由通常甚至被体验为必然性。
Like, imagine LGBT plus boy, at least biologic looks, no.
比如，想象一个LGBT+的男孩，生物学上的男孩。
He experiences deep his identity as either third one or woman or whatever, something third, and in some sense, he has no choice.
他深刻地体验到自己的身份，或是第三性，或是女性，或是其他，从某种意义上说，他没有选择。
But again, this is true freedom.
但再次，这才是真正的自由。
It's like love.
就像爱情。
I always like this example.
我总是喜欢这个例子。
Love has to be free.
爱情必须是自由的。
I cannot order you to fall in love.
我不能命令你去爱上某人。
But isn't it that love is freedom experienced as the utter necessity?
但爱情不就是作为绝对必然性体验的自由吗？
Like when you are truly in love, you cannot say, oh, this person whom I love is too difficult, confused, let me choose another object.
当你真正恋爱时，你不能说，哦，我爱的这个人太难了、太混乱了，让我选择另一个对象。
No, you cannot go out.
不，你不能离开。
Love is your fate.
爱情是你的命运。
And precisely as such, it is free.
正因为如此，它是自由的。
So, as somebody trained in psychoanalysis, theoretically only, you know, no, I would never do practice.
所以，作为一个接受过精神分析理论训练的人，仅限理论，我永远不会做实践。
Some students years ago wanted me to be their psychoanalyst.
几年前，一些学生想让我成为他们的精神分析师。
And you know what was my reaction?
你知道我的反应是什么吗？
I told them, if you want me to be your analyst, then you are really crazy and you need one.
我告诉他们，如果你想让我成为你的分析师，那么你真的疯了，你需要一个……
But what I'm saying is that, you know, Freudian psychoanalysis gives the thick background of all the traumatic dimension of the topic done by LGBT+.
但我想说的是，你知道，弗洛伊德的精神分析提供了所有LGBT+主题背后那些创伤维度的深刻背景。
But again, I don't like this idea which sometimes you can feel it that basically sexuality is three in this superficial sense,
但再说一遍，我不喜欢这个想法，“有时你会感觉到”，基本上性别在这种肤浅的意义上是自由的，
you flirt with this, with that option, and then the evil patriarchy comes and tells you no binary, this, that, and so on and so on.
你随便地思考了一下这个选项，随便地思考了一下那个选项，然后邪恶的父权制来了，告诉你不要二元对立，等等。
No, Freud was right.
不，弗洛伊德是对的。
We are extraordinary, complex, divided persons, and the great lesson of Jacques Lacan is that There is always a minimal gap between what you want and what you really desire.
我们是非常特别的，复杂的，分裂的人，而雅克·拉康的伟大教训是，你想要的和你真正渴望的之间总有一个最小的差距。
It's quite often that what you declare that you want is part of a struggle against what unconsciously you desire.
很多时候，你宣称你想要的东西是你与无意识欲望斗争的一部分。
And I think out of my respect for LGBT plus and so on, people, to conclude, yes, maybe Then I will really stop if you are stupid enough to believe, but I will.
出于我对LGBT+等人的尊重，最后，是的，也许然后我会真的停下来，如果你够愚蠢去相信，但我会。
You know what attracts me, and I was so proud when LGBT plus many people, okay now it's more complex, it's LGBTQ whatever and so on.
你知道什么吸引我，当“LGBT+很多人”，好吧现在更复杂了，是“LGBTQ+无论什么”。
You know what's my basic idea in this agreement with some strength.
你知道，我对这个共识的基本观点是什么，
How do you, maybe if you read some of my books you must know this line, how do you define
“你怎么定义”，也许如果你读过我的一些书，你必须知道这句话，“怎么定义”
Either in an empirical way, which is, maybe there are other identities that the list is never complete.
要么以经验的方式，也就是说，也许还有其他恒等式，但这个列表永远不会列完。
So plus stands for, let's see, if you say, I'm neither L, not G, B, blah, blah, the space is open for you.
所以加号代表的是，比如说，如果你说，我既不是L，也不是G，B，等等，空间是为你打开的。
But I propose a much more radical reading.
但我提出一个更加激进的解读。
As subject, we are basically this plus itself, escaping every identification.
作为主体，我们基本上就是这个加号本身，逃避每一种认同。
That's why, I'm sorry, I didn't go more into philosophy, that's why modern subjectivity is more feminine.
这就是为什么，对不起，我没有更多地深入哲学，这就是为什么现代主体性更加女性化。
And that's the great thing about psychoanalysis, what I mean by this.
这就是精神分析学的伟大之处，我的意思是这个。
You know, hysteria for Freud, and Lacan points this out, It's the basic form of critique of ideology in practice.
你知道，对弗洛伊德而言的歇斯底里，拉康指出，这是实践中意识形态批判的基本形式。
Why? Because, as Lacombe points out in a wonderful way,
为什么？因为，正如拉康以一种精彩的方式指出的，
the basic mechanism of ideology is ideological symbolic identification.
意识形态的基本机制是意识形态符号认同。
The existing order tells you, gives you a space of what you are.
现有的秩序告诉你，给你一个空间，让你知道你是谁。
You are a man, a professor, or whatever.
你是一个男人，一个教授，或者其他什么。
But the original hysterical question is,
但原始的歇斯底里问题是，
why am I what you are saying that I am?
为什么我是你所说的那样？
The doubt into your symbolic identity provided by society.
对社会提供的你的象征身份的怀疑。
That's the, this is why in contrast to those who think that the Cartesian cogito, this pure modern subject is masculine.
这就是为什么，相反于这个观点，即那些认为笛卡尔的“我思”的这个纯粹的现代主体性是男性的观点，
No, it's feminine, and we don't have time to go into this, but this is a wonderful topic.
不，它是女性化的，我们没有时间深入讨论这个，但这是一个精彩的话题。
You know that that's why already in his age, early 17th century, Descartes was extremely popular among women who immediately got this.
你知道，这就是为什么在他的时代，17世纪初，笛卡尔在女性中极受欢迎，她们立刻就理解了这一点。
Cogito, aha, it's not men, there is a space for us.
我思故我在，啊哈，这不是男性化的，这其中有我们的空间。
And women, not just Queen Christina of the stupid movie with Greta Garbo of Sweden.
而且女性，不仅仅是瑞典的格丽塔·嘉宝那部愚蠢电影中的克里斯蒂娜女王。
But it was extraordinary what movement among women was triggered.
但这在女性中引发的运动是非凡的。
And all this is so important today if we live also psychologically in an era of paradoxes, my God.
如果我们在心理上也生活在一个充满悖论的时代，那么今天所有这些都是如此重要，我的上帝。
It's permissiveness which is turning around into strict regulation with all the politically correct rules and so on and so on.
宽容正在转变为严格的监管，包括所有政治正确的规则等等。
With all this focus on, again, permissiveness and pleasure, what we get is more than ever impotence, frigidity and so on and so on.
再次，由于所有这些焦点都集中在放纵和享乐上，我们得到的比以往任何时候都更加阳痿、性冷淡等等。
Sex is a big mess.
性是一团糟。
We have to accept this.
我们必须接受这一点。
In itself, it's a big mess.
本身，它就是一团糟。
And here, although at other points I disagree with her, here I agree with Judith Butler
在这里，尽管在其他方面我不同意她，但在这里我同意朱迪思·巴特勒
where she pointed out how the basic, this would be the minimum of what you mentioned, this surplus enjoyment as opposed to pleasure.
她指出基本的，这将是你提到的最低限度，这种剩余的享受而不是快乐。
You know that sexuality always gets entangled in these paradoxes.
你知道性总是陷入这些悖论中。
Your desire is repressed, but then it turns around into desire for repression itself.
你的欲望被压抑，但然后它变成了对压抑本身的欲望。
The very mode you try to repress your desire turns into an additional source of enjoyment and so on and so on.
你试图压抑欲望的方式变成了额外的享乐来源等等。
And I think here, precisely in today's mess of sexual identities, psychoanalysis is needed more than ever now it's really time for me to stop my favorite it's diet coke
我认为，正是在当今性别认同混乱的情况下，精神分析比以往任何时候都更需要，现在我真的是时候停止了，
with cherry taste because this cherry, this is a nice example of this rigid designator it's you recognize it's totally chemical I don't see any link between how real Clarice tastes and that's why I like it.
我最喜欢的樱桃味健怡可乐了，因为这个樱桃，这是这个严格指示符的一个很好的例子，它就是你认识到它完全是化学物质（调制出的味道），我看不出任何真正的樱桃味和它的联系，这就是我喜欢它的原因。
Okay. Thank you, Slav.
好的。谢谢，斯拉夫。
We've got time.
我们还有时间。
I mean, we have to be done by nine because we're both guessing on Steve Bannon's podcast.
我的意思是，我们必须在九点前结束，因为我们俩都要去参加史蒂夫·班农的播客节目。
That's a joke.
这是个玩笑。
Yeah, we have, you know, 20, 25 minutes for question and answer.
是的，我们还有，你知道的，20到25分钟来回答问题。
There are microphones up front, or why don't we use this center one?
前面有麦克风，或者我们为什么不使用这个中间的呢？
So, if you have a question, why don't we line up at the microphone and.
所以，如果你有问题，我们为什么不在麦克风前排队呢。
Yeah, but didn't you tell me there are more microphones?
是的，但你没告诉我还有更多的麦克风吗？
There's one over there too, but let's, in the interest of getting it.
那边也有一个，但让我们快点开始吧。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, you, yeah.
是的，你，是的。
Wait, so.
等等，所以。
Yeah, okay.
是的，好的。
Okay. Is the mic working?
好的。麦克风工作正常吗？
Testing, testing, one, two, three.
测试，测试，一二三。
Can you hear me?
你能听见我吗？
Okay.
好的。
Please. So I guess I noticed although I'm often proclaimed anti-feminist, but it makes me very sad.
请。所以我猜我注意到虽然我经常被宣称为反女权主义者，但这让我非常难过。
Is there any woman in the line?
排队的有女性吗？
No, you know why I'm saying this seriously?
没有，你知道我为什么这么认真地说这个吗？
Because, for example, I'm very good friend with many black people and we have this type of wonderful relationship where,
因为，比如说，我和许多黑人朋友关系很好，我们之间有这种奇妙的关系，
I don't dare to give you examples, all the time we exchange dirty racist innuendos, jokes and so on.
我不敢给你举例子，我们总是交换带有种族歧视的下流暗示、笑话等等。
And we love each other for that, you know.
我们因此相爱，你知道的。
And so once I was with a black friend of mine, I was tired. I was just polite.
所以有一次我和一个黑人朋友在一起，我很累。我只是保持礼貌。
And he was in a panic.
他感到恐慌。
He told me, are you mad at me or what?
他告诉我，你对我生气了吗？
Where are your dirty jokes?
你的下流笑话呢？
So what I'm saying is that nonetheless, a proof that I am a feminist, it's a purely theoretical one.
所以我要说的是，尽管如此，作为我是女权主义者的证据，这纯粹是理论上的证据，
I am a Hegelian, and in the last 20, 30 years, practically,
我是一个黑格尔主义者，在过去的20、30年里，实际上，所有关于黑格尔的好书都是由女性写的。
Rebecca Comay, even Judith Butler, something about desire, her first book, very good one, is on Hegel.
丽贝卡·科迈，甚至朱迪思·巴特勒，关于欲望的某些内容，她的第一本书，非常好，是关于黑格尔的。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
是的，是的，是的。
So, I'm sorry, I'm again getting lost, please.
所以，对不起，我又跑题了，请继续。
Testing one, two, three.
测试一二三。
All right.
好的。
Yeah, but do you in.
是的，但是你在。
Testing one, two, three.
测试一二三。
Do you hear him?
你听到他了吗？
Okay, okay.
好的，好的。
So I guess my question would be, so for a little context,
所以我想我的问题会是，为了提供一点背景，
in say medieval society you sort of had, you would have, you would have the concept of the carnival was a very common sort of thing.
比如说在中世纪社会，你会有，你会有“狂欢”这样一个非常常见的概念。
Yes, and then you had a sort of similar things in similar societies like in ancient Rome.
是的，然后你在类似的社会中，比如古罗马，也有类似的事情。
I think I've heard the anecdote of how they'd have a festival or something where they'd make the slave the emperor, the king for Dan and at the end of the day they'd kill him.
我想我听说过一个轶事，关于他们会有一个节日或什么的，在那一天他们会让一个奴隶成为皇帝，国王，然后在一天结束时杀死他。
So you sort of had this sort of publicization and sort of social acceptance of this sort of bizarre, irrational, into the sort of form of public release.
所以对这种奇怪的、非理性的东西，进行这种公众化和社会性的接受，以某种公众释放的形式。
Do you think that the sort, do you think that a sort of modern sort of sense of trying, sort of like 15th, 16th, 17th century, trying to cut, trying to lift the average person outside
您认为那种尝试，就像是在15、16、17世纪那样试图将普通人从“狂欢”的状态中提升出来的现代感觉，
of that carnival, do you think that the sort of 20th and 21st century as sort of seeing the sort of carnival and sort of this very sort of strict regime that you might see spoken about when someone like Foucault,
到了20和21世纪，是否我们看到了“狂欢”与那种您可能在像福柯这样的人物作品中所谈论的严格制度之间的一种融合和合并？
do you think that the 20th and 21st centuries are sort of that the carnival and this sort of order that we tried to create without it are sort of converged and merged?
换句话说，20和21世纪是否见证了我们试图创建的秩序与“狂欢”这种状态之间的交汇和融合？
Do you think that the sort of shame that is sort of being seen on the public level is at the very consequences of those merging?
您认为在公众层面上看到的那种羞耻是否正是这些合并的后果？
It's a very precise question.
这是一个非常精确的问题。
I'm still in some sense, sorry if I disappoint you here, attached to modernity.
从某种意义上说，如果我让你失望了，我很抱歉，我仍然依恋现代性。
I still think maybe not early modernity, but French Revolution is a mega event for me and so on.
我仍然认为，也许不是早期的现代性，但法国革命对我而言是一个重大事件。
So my point would be that already what happened in the 20th century was a kind of dark underside of carnival.
所以我的观点是，20 世纪发生的事情已经是狂欢节的黑暗面。
Do you know probably, did you read the book, it's a classic on carnival among others by Michael Bakhtin on Francois Rablé, he elaborated this notion of carnival.
你读过这本书吗，这是迈克尔·巴赫金（Michael Bakhtin）关于弗朗索瓦·拉布莱（Francois Rablé）的关于狂欢节的经典著作，他详细阐述了狂欢节的概念。
But my friend, the German art theorist, Boris Groys, recently got hold of archives of Bakhtin.
但我的朋友，德国艺术理论家鲍里斯·格罗伊斯，最近得到了巴赫金的档案。
He survived the purges because he moved to Kazan, some smaller city, and the big Moscow bureaucracy forgot about him.
他因为搬到了喀山，一个较小的城市，而幸存下来，因为大莫斯科官僚机构忘记了他。
And what's so fascinating is that, it was a unanimous message from his private notes that for him, the big carnival that he didn't dare to mention where the Stalinist purpose.
而令人着迷的是，他的私人笔记中一致传达出这样的信息：对他来说，这场他不敢提及的Stalinism狂欢节的目的在哪里。
Because it was, you know, today you are a king, member of Politburo, tomorrow you are an English spy, a British spy.
因为，你知道，今天你是国王、政治局委员，明天你就是英国间谍、英国间谍。
It was, and even in, there is also a carnival aspect.
过去，甚至现在，也有狂欢的一面。
Some friends of mine, black people are exploring it.
我的一些黑人朋友正在探索这个。
Ku Klux Klan in its, sorry for this horrible term, I mean it ironically, golden era in 1920s.
三K党在它的，抱歉用这个可怕的术语，我是讽刺地说，“黄金时代”，在1920年代。
You know, it was the end of the week carnival for the white people.
你知道，这是白人的周末狂欢。
Let's have some fun.
让我们找点乐子。
Let's lynch some black guys.
让我们来吊死一些黑人。
let's rape some black women and so on and so on.
让我们强奸一些黑人女性
So I think that I always found it problematic to oppose this rigid order of a society and this moment of freedom where the king is a servant, the servant is a king, all that stuff.
所以我认为，我总是发现将社会的这种严格秩序和王者为奴、奴者为王的自由时刻对立起来是有问题的，所有的这些。
I think that in most of the time, carnivals were simply a kind of a libidical supplement in an intermediate way, even supporting the existing order which you should not forget this.
我认为，大多数时候，狂欢仅仅是一种中间性的力比多补充，甚至支持现存的秩序，这一点你不应该忘记。
Don't idealize medieval times.
不要理想化中世纪。
There are many things we don't know.
有很多事情我们不知道。
I mean, we don't know, but how brutal oppression was there?
我的意思是，我们不知道，那里的压迫有多残酷？
I mean, you know, sometimes we idealize them as a kind of a small organic community, extremely brutal times.
我的意思是，你知道，有时我们会将这个非常残酷的时代理想化为一种小型有机社区。
So what I am, of course, there are attempts to see even in mass sport events and so on, new forms of cardio, but for me, again,
所以我的意思是，当然，有人试图在大众体育事件等中看到新形式的狂欢，但对我来说，再次，
the least I would say is that there is also a very dark side
我至少会说，这里也有一个非常黑暗的面
For example, in Nazi literature, when, no, it's too crazy to say that's too horrible, that Auschwitz was a carnival.
例如，在纳粹文献中，当，不，说奥斯威辛是一个狂欢太疯狂了，太可怕了。
But the way Kristallnacht, you know when 38, when Jews were beaten,
但是水晶之夜的方式，你知道1938年，犹太人被殴打，
some of them lynched and so on, has a clear structure of a carnival.
其中一些人被捕链（译注：被暴力攻击或被群众非法处决的行为）等，具有明显的狂欢结构。
It even up to a point, as is typical for a carnival, run out of control, and that's the very sad thing.
它甚至在一定程度上，像典型的狂欢一样，失去了控制，这是非常悲哀的事情。
It wasn't that it was planned by Goebbels or whom.
这不是因为它是由戈培尔或其他人计划的。
It was, but even they were surprised by how it exploded.
即使他们也对它的爆炸式发展感到惊讶。
So again, I'm just saying don't also don't idealize the carnival.
所以再次，我只是说不要理想化狂欢。
The carnival is for me quite often that, or another element, it's not the same as carnival, I know, but one of the nicest memories from communism that I have is, I didn't like it,
狂欢对我来说很多时候，或者是另一个元素，我知道它不同于狂欢，但我从communism时期拥有的最美好的记忆之一是，我不喜欢它，
but how it's not carnival, but the role played there by political jokes, jokes against those in power.
但是它不是狂欢，而是政治笑话、针对当权者的笑话在那里扮演的角色。
I always had a suspicion, although some people were arrested for telling them, that those in power were fully aware that it has this carnivalesque notion of,
尽管有人因讲这些笑话而被逮捕，我总是有一种怀疑，那些当权者完全意识到它具有这种狂欢式的概念，
if you don't allow people to let their steam off, how do you call it, through telling jokes, then you will have real protests.
如果你不允许人们通过讲笑话来发泄，那么你将会面临真正的抗议。
So it's not true, but there is a rumor. It's not true, but it's the right insight that secret police departments, police in Eastern Europe, communist times, had secret departments fabricating jokes.
但有一个谣言，它不是真的，但它是正确的洞察，即秘密警察部门，在东欧communism时期，有秘密部门专门制造笑话。
Not jokes against the Western decadence, but jokes against their own police.
不是针对西方堕落的笑话，而是针对他们自己的警察的笑话。
The idea was allow, give these people a way to express their anger to, you know, and so on and so on.
这个想法是允许，给这些人一个表达他们愤怒的方式，你知道，等等。
And again, with Stalinism, it's absolutely clear this functioning,
再次说到Stalinism，它的功能是绝对清晰的，
this carnivalesque dimension,
这种狂欢式的维度，
especially when the purgaries got serious.
特别是当清洗变得严重时。
The true Stalinist purgaries were 34, 36.
真正的Stalinist式清洗是在34年、36年。
And it's pure carnival in what sense?
从什么意义上说这是纯粹的狂欢节？
Do you know that, for example, in those two years, like 70% of the central committee members were liquidated,
你知道吗，比如在那两年里，大约70%的中央委员会成员被清除，超过一半的军队高级将领被清除，是最糟的时候。
It's very interesting to know this in Ukraine, where that's what I call a perk.
在Ukraine了解这一点非常有趣，即我所说的清洗。
In 1934, Ukrainian Central Committee had 200 members, the central committee of the party.
1934年，Ukraine中央委员会有200名成员，是Party的中央委员会。
You know how many of them were alive three years later, no two years later, three.
你知道两年后还活着的有多少人吗，不，三年后，3个。
That's what I call a perch.
那就是我所说的清洗。
So again, I didn't answer all the depth of your question I know, I'm just saying that Bakhtin himself is misread when he's presented as the guy who somehow just celebrated carnival.
所以再次，我知道我没有回答你问题的全部深度，我只是说，当巴赫金被描绘成一个庆祝狂欢的人时，他本人被误读了。
No, he was well aware of the dark aspects of a carnival of this other side.
不，他非常清楚狂欢节这种事物黑暗面的存在。
Otherwise, I am an idiot, but not complete idiot, which means that I am well aware of the finesse of your question, the other aspects.
否则，我是个傻瓜，但不是彻底的傻瓜，这意味着我非常清楚你问题的微妙之处，其他方面。
But now I will just limit myself to this general point, don't overestimate some kind of a, non-emancipatory power of carnival.
但现在我将仅限于这个一般性的观点，不要高估狂欢、某种非解放性力量。
And this is why my, this is why I'm also not so fascinated,
这就是为什么我，这就是为什么我也不那么着迷，
you know, we had not so much here but in Europe,
你知道，我们这里没有那么多，但在欧洲，你知道几年前在伊斯坦布尔的那个大规模民粹运动。
One million people protesting against Erdogan or in Egypt and so on.
一百万人抗议埃尔多安或在埃及等地。
I always have a deep mistrust against this big million people there.
我总是对这些大规模的百万人抗议深感不信任。
What interests me is how to say after you get drunk, the morning after, no?
我感兴趣的是，该怎么说，喝醉后的第二天早晨（译注：运动成功后的转天）？
How this energy unleashed is then translated into a new order.
这种释放的能量如何转化为新的秩序。
Usually, carnivals don't produce a new order.
通常，狂欢不会产生新的秩序。
They are just a momentary explosion,
它们只是一种短暂的爆发，然后事情会回到旧秩序。
And that's what I don't like.
这就是我不喜欢的。
I think that the really difficult thing is not to organize one million people shouting there.
我认为真正困难的事情不是组织一百万人在那里喊叫。
No, but to make a change felt when things return to normal, to establish a new normal.
不，但是当事情恢复正常时，要做出改变，建立新的常态。
That's why years ago, you remember the movie, how is that, oh my God, the movie about.
这就是为什么多年前，你还记得那部电影，那是怎么的，哦，天哪，那部关于......
Vendetta Part II.
《V字仇杀队2》。
Did you see the movie?
你看过那部电影吗？
At the end, triumph, people break the police code, they won.
在结尾，人们打破了警察的封锁，他们赢了。
Okay, but what happened then?
好吧，但那之后发生了什么？
How is the new power structured?
新的权力是如何构建的？
That's the big problem today.
这是今天的大问题。
Okay, let's see if we can get a couple more.
好的，让我们看看是否还有更多问题。
I'm sorry, I will be much faster.
对不起，我会更快一点。
I understand.
我明白了。
Thank you, sir.
谢谢，先生。
I mean, I will have to give you a quicker answer.
我的意思是，我将不得不给你一个更快的回答。
Sorry. Yeah, please.
对不起。是的，请问。
Howdy. I've got more sort of foreign policy question.
嗨。我有一个更倾向于外交政策的问题。
And so for me, when you were talking about Russia and Ukraine, it didn't feel to me as though you really adequately addressed the consequences of a more confrontational policy against Russia,
所以对我来说，当你谈论Russia和Ukraine时，我感觉你没有真正充分地解决对Russia采取更具对抗性政策的后果，
which, as you said, words are not just words, should always be taken seriously, especially in Putin's case.
正如你所说，话语不仅仅是话语，总是应该被认真对待，尤其是在普京的案例中。
And he has, and his government has brought up nuclear war, mutually assured destruction on many occasions now.
他和他的政府现在已经多次提到核战争，相互确保毁灭。
And I was just wondering how in your mind is it considered moral or could it be considered moral to advocate for a confrontational stance against Russia
我只是想知道，在你看来，当这种立场可能的后果如此严重时，主张对Russia采取对抗性立场在道德上是否可以接受，或者能被认为是道德的？
Please just repeat the last word.
请重复最后一句。
How could it be considered moral to adopt a confrontational stance against Russia when the possible consequences of adopting that stance are so high,
当采取那种立场可能的后果如此之高时，如何认为采取对抗Russia的立场是道德的，
you know, i.e. mutually assured destruction?
你知道，即相互确保毁灭？
But I totally agree with this.
但我完全同意这一点。
But why do you think that, isn't it that the way I see it, that Russia started the topic of using tactical nuclear weapons and all that stuff and so on and so on?
但你为什么会这么想，我看到的是，Russia主动引起了战术核武器之类的话题？
And I think, first I don't believe that Putin is a madman and so on, who just waits to press the button.
我首先不认为普京是一个疯子等等，就等着按下按钮。
I think he's precisely playing on this fear.
我认为他正是在利用这种恐惧。
My God, what if I go crazy and so on and so on.
我的天，如果我疯了怎么办等等。
So you know what's my problem?
所以你知道我的问题是什么吗？
Many of my friends by this line whenever NATO does something it must be bad or whatever.
我的许多朋友都认为，只要北约做了什么事情，那就一定是不好的。
But my problem here is, okay, I tell you this.
但我这里的问题是，好吧，我告诉你这个。
We can talk for hours because I'm also very critical of Ukrainians.
我们可以谈上几个小时，因为我对Ukraine人也有很多批评。
First, the mistakes, and it's two weak words, mistakes they made, point to this is the darkest part, how?
首先，错误，这个词太弱了，他们犯的错误，指向这是最黑暗的部分，
Even now, the West is already, everything is set in motion to prepare whatever you call it, I hate these words, neoliberal colonization from the West of Ukraine.
即使现在，西方已经一切准备就绪，无论你怎么称呼它，我讨厌这些词，来自Ukraine西部的新自由主义殖民。
Do you know that according to some sources, one-third of best Ukrainian land is already owned by big American agricultural companies and so on.
你知道吗，根据一些来源，Ukraine最好的土地已经有三分之一被大型美国农业公司等拥有。
They are putting terrible pressure now already on Ukraine, this open totally to free market, blah, blah, all that.
他们现在已经对Ukraine施加了可怕的压力，这完全对自由市场开放，等等，所有这些。
So I'm well aware on this.
所以我对此非常清楚。
You know what's the danger I see here?
你知道我在这里看到的危险是什么吗？
Some of my leftist friends who say, okay, if you attack, if we give arms to Ukraine,
我的一些左翼朋友说，好吧，如果你攻击，如果我们给Ukraine提供武器，
it means we support our military industry, blah, blah.
这意味着我们支持我们的军工产业，等等。
I ask them a very simple question.
我问他们一个非常简单的问题。
So what should be our message to Ukrainians?
那么我们对Ukraine人的传达什么信息呢？
Sometimes what my friends are saying, telling me sounds like,
有时我的朋友们告诉我的听起来像是，
okay the attack is horrible, but on behalf of global peace and so on, Ukrainians should suffer a little bit, make a compromise and so on and so on.
好吧，攻击是可怕的，但是为了全球和平等等，Ukraine人应该稍微忍受一下，做出妥协等等。
You know who went here to the end and it costs me his friendship more or less Yanis Varoufakis, I was shocked when Taliban won in Afghanistan, he posted, tweet, whatever, but his point was,
你知道谁将这点推到了极致，这几乎让我失去了他的友谊，扬尼斯·瓦鲁法基斯，塔利班在阿富汗获胜时，我震惊于他发的推文，但他的观点是，
it's a great defeat of American imperialism.
这是美国帝国主义的重大失败。
It's a great victory.
这是一次伟大的胜利。
Then he says, okay, women will suffer, we should help them, but nonetheless, so his message is that we should say to Afghani, we mean, yes, it's horrible, but sorry,
然后他说，好吧，女性会受苦，我们应该帮助她们，但不管怎样，所以他的信息是，我们应该对阿富汗人说，是的，这很可怕，但抱歉，
there is a higher interest of defeating American imperialism, blah, blah, blah, just suffer.
有一个更高的利益是打败美国帝国主义，等等，只能忍受。
This is for me the most horrible thing to do.
对我来说，这是最可怕的事情。
For example, when people also, some of my leftist friends, condemned, sorry, not Norway, Finland and Sweden, their desire to join NATO.
例如，当一些我的左派朋友谴责，抱歉，不是挪威，是芬兰和瑞典，他们想加入北约的愿望。
Again, my point is, and I know I have high political connections there, they were scared like shit.
再次，我的观点是，我在那里有高层政治联系，他们害怕得要命。
So what should we tell them?
那么我们应该告诉他们什么？
Sorry guys, you are in danger but you know we don't want to support our military industrial complex or what.
抱歉，伙计们，你们处于危险中，但你知道我们不想支持我们的军工复合体，或者怎样。
So I think that this should be an ABC of progressive politics.
所以我认为这应该是进步政治的基础知识。
Never elevate your cause into a big cause for which then you demand subordinated group to sacrifice their interests.
永远不要将你的事业说成是一个大事业，然后你要求下属为此牺牲他们的利益。
No, no, again, I'm very critical here of Ukrainians.
不，不，再次，我在这里对Ukraine人非常批判。
But, okay, I ask you, and sincerely, it's not rhetoric.
但是，好吧，我问你，真诚地，这不是花言巧语。
What, yes, what should the West have done, Western Europe, when Russia attacked Ukraine?
那么，是的，当Russia攻击Ukraine时，西方，西欧应该做什么？
That's a big question, but I just, I don't see how the suffering of Ukrainians can be put, you know, how we can say that it's better to have the whole world suffer than to just have Ukraine suffer.
这是一个大问题，但我只是，我不明白如何表达Ukraine人的苦难，你知道，我们如何能说让全世界受苦比让Ukraine受苦更好。
I agree, it's horrible for that to happen.
我同意，这种情况发生是可怕的。
But when you're talking about world war here.
但当你在这里谈论世界大战时。
Already, in what you said, some factual implications that I find problematic.
我认为你所说的一些事实含义已经存在问题。
Why do you think it would have stopped in Ukraine?
你为什么认为它会停在Ukraine？
Well, I'd just like to say also, I'm not talking about what you said with Afghanistan, where it's this conceptual American empire that we're fighting.
吧，我还想说，我不是在谈论你所说的阿富汗问题，我们正在与这个概念上的美利坚帝国作战。
This is talking about something that could happen to everybody, right?
这是在谈论每个人都可能发生的事情，对吗？
I think that the possibility of nuclear confrontation should be avoided at all costs,
我认为应该不惜一切代价避免核对抗的可能性，
and if that means not necessarily giving Russia part of Ukraine, but that means adopting a more peaceable, you know, stance right to negotiate.
如果这意味着不一定要把Ukraine的一部分给Russia，但这意味着采取更和平的谈判立场。
I think that that's what has to be done.
我认为这就是必须要做的。
Why? Okay, I hear your point.
为什么？好的，我听到了你的观点。
Of course, we are all afraid of not only of nuclear war, but even larger European war and so on and so on.
当然，我们都害怕的不仅仅是核战争，还有更大规模的欧洲战争等等。
But the problem for me in Ukraine is nonetheless that I see in what Putin is doing.
但我在Ukraine的问题是，尽管如此，我在普京的所作所为中看到了。
It's not just Ukraine.
这不仅仅是Ukraine。
It's he began in where not Chechnya, then it was Grazia, Georgia, and so on.
他从哪里开始的，不是车臣，然后是格鲁吉亚，等等。
It goes around.
它在蔓延。
He openly says the greatest tragedy of the 20th century was the disintegration of the Soviet Union, and he is openly saying defining Russian sphere.
他公开表示，20世纪最大的悲剧是苏联的解体，并且他公开地定义了Russia的势力范围。
And I think that first we should clarify what Russia is.
我认为我们首先应该澄清什么是Russia。
where I disagree with some of my leftist friends is that they are so obsessed by NATO and so on that automatically you have to be, if you are opposed to big Western imperialism, you
我与一些左翼朋友的不同之处在于，他们对北约等如此着迷，以至于他们自动认为，如果你反对大西方的帝国主义，
somehow have to be at least partially on the good side.
你不得不至少在某种程度上站在好的一边。
But my point is a very brutal one.
但我的观点非常残酷。
I'm not comparing Putin with Hitler, but what would you then say Germany 1939?
我并不是将普京与希特勒相比较，但你怎么看1939年的德国呢？
Let's give, isn't this the same logic?
让我们给予希特勒捷克斯洛伐克只是为了保持欧洲和平，这不是同样的逻辑吗？
Let's give to Hitler Czechoslovakia just to keep peace in Europe.
让我们给予希特勒捷克斯洛伐克只是为了保持欧洲和平。
And then.
然后呢。
No, because, I mean, Hitler didn't have the capacity to, Hitler didn't have the capacity to level New York with, you know, the push of a button.
不，因为，我的意思是，希特勒没有能力只需按一个按钮就能夷平纽约。
Yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
Okay, I agree, but again, my problem is, so what's your idea?
好吧，我同意，但再次，我的问题是，那么你的想法是什么？
It's just that let's make compromises, compromises to,
就是说，让我们做出妥协，做出妥协，
I think this doesn't work.
我认为这不可行。
It works in the short term maybe, but then it goes on, it goes on, it goes, it goes on.
也许短期内有效，但然后它继续下去，继续下去，就这样继续。
I'm absolutely fanatically to avoid with peace, but okay, let's be concrete.
我绝对狂热地想要和平地解决问题，但是好吧，让我们具体一点。
Now even Putin is giving hints, now maybe that it's more or less a stalemate, kind of in Ukraine, Ukrainians recapture some parts of it.
现在，即使普京也在暗示，现在可能在Ukraine形成了一种僵局，Ukraine人重新夺回了其中的一些地区。
Yes, there are now maybe conditions for some negotiated peace.
是的，现在可能存在一些谈判和平的条件。
But are you aware that these conditions were created by Western help?
但你意识到这些条件是由西方帮助创造的吗？
Without Western help, Ukraine would have collapsed in a week or two.
没有西方的帮助，Ukraine会在一两周内崩溃。
So I think, at least let's admit this, I don't see in the West some mega, in spite of rhetoric occasional, some mega rhetoric.
所以我认为，至少让我们承认这一点，我在西方没有看到一些宏大的言论，尽管偶尔会有一些宏大的言论。
Even, I think, do you remember immediately when Russia announced the attack?
甚至，我认为，你还记得Russia宣布进攻时的情况吗？
You know what was first Biden's, and I'm no sympathizer of Biden's reaction, it was incredible.
你知道拜登最初的反应是什么，我并不是拜登的支持者，那真是令人难以置信。
When he was asked what will be the countermeasures, Biden said, it depends how radical Russian interventions will be.
当被问及将采取什么反措施时，拜登说，这取决于Russia干预的激进程度。
If they want just part of the Southeast, it's one thing.
如果他们只想要东南部的一部分，那是一回事。
If they want all of it.
如果他们想要全部。
So it's incredible how Biden showed immediately an openness to compromise and so on and so on.
所以，拜登立即表现出愿意妥协的态度，真是令人难以置信。
I just don't accept this obsession with Russia has to save its face and so on and so on.
我就是不接受这种对Russia必须保全面子的强迫症。
But okay, one thing, okay, let's not lose time, but to give you an example where I think Ukraine should be brutally criticized.
但好吧，一件事，好吧，我们不浪费时间，但给你一个我认为应该严厉批评Ukraine的例子。
You know how Ukraine reacted to the fact, do you remember, that this year's Nobel Peace Prize
你知道Ukraine如何反应于今年的诺贝尔和平奖授予了一些Ukraine慈善组织和一些白Russia人以及一些Russia人，这些人半被捕，他们真的在Russia为和平而战。
Ukraine protested, claiming that although they protest the war in Russia, but they didn't really achieve anything,
Ukraine抗议，声称尽管他们在Russia抗议战争，但他们并没有真正取得任何成果，
it's a shame to give peace Nobel Prize to citizens of a state which is now attacking Ukraine, this is sheer madness, I think.
将和平奖授予一个正在攻击Ukraine的国家的公民，这完全是疯狂，
Ukrainians here spoke the same language as Putin and his ideologies.
我认为在这里，Ukraine人说的是与普京及其意识形态相同的语言。
They spoke as if it's a conflict, and here I also disagree with Ukraine.
他们说得好像是一场冲突，这里我也不同意Ukraine的观点。
You know, they like to speak about we are defending Europe.
你知道，他们喜欢说我们在保卫欧洲。
It's like Europe against Russia.
就好像是欧洲对抗Russia。
They speak almost the same language as Dugin, Putin's ideologies here.
他们几乎是在说与普京的意识形态家杜金相同的语言。
No, we should insist on it.
不，我们应该坚持这一点。
This is a struggle inherent to Europe itself.
这是欧洲内部自身的斗争。
We have our own fascists and so on, neo-fascists, internal to Russia itself and so on and so on.
我们有自己的法西斯分子，新法西斯分子，Russia内部的法西斯分子等等。
If we lose this universal approach and go into this water, you know, Ukraine is defending Europe and so on, we are lost.
如果我们失去这种普遍的做法并进入这片水域，你知道，Ukraine正在保卫欧洲等等，我们就迷失了。
Do I agree with you?
我同意你吗？
Let's end on universalism.
让我们以普遍主义结束。
Let's end.
让我们结束。
Okay.
好的。
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉。
Yes.
是的。
I know more people have questions.
我知道还有更多人有问题。
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉。
We're done at 9.
我们9点结束。
It's already 9.
现在已经9点了。
So we're going to have to cut it short.
所以我们得缩短一点。
Okay.
好的。
I will try to be short.
我会尽量简短。
You know what?
你知道吗？
My bad taste joke here.
我这里的糟糕笑话。
I will try to give you.
我会尽量给你。
Wait.
等等。
I need that button.
我需要那个按钮。
You know what I'm tempted to do?
你知道我想做什么吗？
It's a bad joke.
这是个糟糕的笑话。
to give you this so deep Zen Buddhist answers, you know, clap with one hand or whatever.
给你这种深奥的禅宗佛教回答，你知道的，单手拍掌之类的。
Okay, we have, I will try to be fast.
好的，我们有，我会尽快。
Let me start off by saying, oh, sorry, yeah.
让我从说起，哦，对不起，是的。
Let me start off by saying it's a great honor for me to meet someone of your own on the left.
让我开始说，能够见到你这样一位左翼人士对我来说是莫大的荣幸。
Sorry.
对不起。
Oh, listen, let's, wait, we're going to have to end it and then why don't you come up and we'll talk to him.
哦，听着，我们等等，我们得结束了，然后你为什么不过来，我们会和他谈谈。
I got a brief question, please.
我有个简短的问题，请问。
Real quick.
快点。
How do we both show solidarity with people in the third world and the imperial periphery and sort of kind of concentrate our efforts on fighting the surge in fascism at home?
我们如何既向第三世界和帝国主义边缘地区的人民表达团结，又集中我们的努力对抗国内法西斯主义的兴起？
Sorry, I didn't get it.
对不起，我没听清。
Did you get it?
你听清了吗？
Can you say it once more then?
你能再说一遍吗？
Yeah. How do we as Western leftists both show solidarity with people in the third world and, you know, fight imperialism
是的。作为西方左翼人士，我们如何既向第三世界的人民表达团结，又对抗帝国主义
and also combat the growing tide of fascism at home?
同时也对抗国内日益增长的法西斯主义潮流？
Like, is there a contradiction between the two or is there not?
就是说，这两者之间存在矛盾吗？还是说没有？
And if not, which one should we concentrate our efforts on?
如果没有，我们应该集中我们的努力在哪一个方面？
You know, this is a big problem, but look, it was the same situation
你知道，这是个大问题，但是看，情况是一样的
at a different level, totally.
完全不同的层面上。
You know that Germany and Japan were playing already this game.
你知道德国和日本已经在玩这个游戏了。
When Japan occupied in, when, 39, 40, whatever, most of the far east there, they constituted some kind of anti-imperialist league.
当日本在39年、40年或什么时候，占领了远东的大部分地区时，他们成立了某种反帝国主义联盟。
When Germans bribed some peaceniks in the United States here and some leftists in England claiming we should not fight imperialist wars and so on.
当德国人在这里的美国收买了一些和平主义者和英国的一些左翼人士，声称我们不应该为帝国主义战争而战等等。
This is the, this is the, this is the tragical situation.
这就是，这就是，这就是悲剧性的处境。
But nonetheless, even if American intervention in World War II was the intervention of an imperial superpower of each point too, gave an incredible boost to your not only military industry, but to your economy.
但尽管如此，即使美国在第二次世界大战中的介入是一个帝国超级大国的介入，也给的不仅是军事工业，还有给经济带来了难以置信的推动。
Look at the history of the United States.
看看美国的历史。
The Great Recession crisis was not over in 3940.
大萧条危机在39年40年并没有结束。
It's only during the World War II years that American economy really, really exploded.
只有在第二次世界大战期间，美国经济真正地爆炸式增长。
But my answer to you would be this one.
但我给你的回答是这样的。
Yes, all that talk about anti-imperialism, but who are till now these great anti-imperialist friends of Russia?
是的，所有关于反帝国主义的讨论，但直到现在，谁是Russia的那些伟大的反帝国主义朋友？
It is Iran.
是伊朗。
Sorry.
对不起。
It's tremendously important what is happening there.
那里发生的事情极其重要。
It's an incredible thing how women are on the top of an authentic revolution.
女性站在真正革命的最前线是一件不可思议的事情。
Something broke in Iran.
伊朗发生了某种突破。
Russia, it's an incredibly important event.
Russia，这是一个极其重要的事件。
And Russia is on that side.
而且Russia站在那一边。
Then North Korea is sending volunteers.
然后北朝鲜正在派遣志愿者。
than some other similar countries, Taliban of course, Afghanistan and so on.
还有一些其他类似的国家，当然还有塔利班的阿富汗等等。
On the other hand, I'm not such a pessimist.
另一方面，我并不是那么悲观。
If you ask me how to fight imperialism, there are many states, even now, where I'm not a total pessimist, where leftists are in power and are doing a relatively good job.
如果你问我如何对抗帝国主义，即使现在，还有许多国家，我并不完全悲观，左翼掌权并且做得相对不错。
For example, my supreme example, I don't know if you agree, is always because I have friends there.
例如，我最高的例子，我不知道你是否同意，总是因为我在那里有朋友。
Linera Morales, Vice President Bolivia.
林纳·莫拉莱斯，玻利维亚副总统。
In ten years of Morales' power, they did a true miracle.
在莫拉莱斯执政的十年里，他们创造了真正的奇迹。
The standard of living of ordinary people is much higher.
普通人的生活水平大大提高。
That's why you remember there was a coup d'etat and then in so-called free elections, although controlled by the army, Morales forces came back to power.
这就是为什么你还记得那里发生了一场政变，然后在所谓的自由选举中，尽管由军队控制，莫拉莱斯的势力重新掌权。
It's extraordinary what is happening now in Latin America.
拉丁美洲现在发生的事情是非凡的。
Leftism there, it's not just those who screwed it up, like Nicaragua,
那里的左翼主义，不仅仅是那些搞砸了的，比如尼加拉瓜，
Venezuela, and Cuba, with all respect for Cuba,
委内瑞拉和古巴，尽管我对古巴表示所有的尊重，
but they screwed it up basically, no?
但他们基本上搞砸了，不是吗？
No, it's new countries like, okay, Chile, it's problematic.
不，是新的国家，好吧，智利，这是有问题的。
They lost the referendum for constitution.
他们在宪法公投中失败了。
But it's Colombia.
但是是哥伦比亚。
It's Bolivia.
是玻利维亚。
Okay. We'll see.
好吧。我们会看到。
What I'm saying is that I totally agree with you that the real test for the West is not to miss this moment, to take, how should I put it, settling, getting rid of its own imperialist legacy really effectively.
我想说的是，我完全同意你的观点，西方的真正考验是不要是错过这个时刻，是如何解决、如何有效地摆脱自己的帝国主义遗产。
If not, the West will become, maybe survive as an island.
如果不这样，西方可能会成为一个孤岛。
So I totally agree with you.
所以我完全同意你。
I even written a text on it.
我甚至写了一篇文章关于这个话题。
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
That's, let's end there.
就这样，我们在这里结束。
That's, we're way over.
我们已经大大超时了。
We have to, thank you Slavoj.
我们必须，谢谢斯拉沃热。
Thank you everybody.
谢谢大家。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
是的，是的，是的。